<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>From Yize</title>
  <icon>https://yize.blog/icon.png</icon>
  
  <link href="https://yize.blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://yize.blog/"/>
  <updated>2022-12-25T00:14:36.706Z</updated>
  <id>https://yize.blog/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Yize Shen</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - November 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20221225/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20221225/</id>
    <published>2022-12-25T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-25T00:14:36.706Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Thanksgiving-socializing-connections"><a href="#Thanksgiving-socializing-connections" class="headerlink" title="Thanksgiving, socializing, connections"></a>Thanksgiving, socializing, connections</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-11/ma-thanksgiving.jpeg" alt="placeholder" style=""><span class="image-caption">placeholder</span><img src="../images/oj-2022-11/uxa-hotpot.jpeg" alt="placeholder" style=""><span class="image-caption">placeholder</span><p>Made dumplings at Ma sister’s house this Thanksgiving, and a day after hosted a hotpot night with UXA. Before I realized it, I was surounded by care and affection from the people I knew.</p><img src="../images/oj-2022-11/toggl-f22.png" alt="hmmm" style=""><span class="image-caption">hmmm</span><p>Nancy metioned CMU is a special place to be in, started to resonate with the thought more and more. On toggl it says I spent 313 hours socializing the past 3 month, more than all of my classes this semester combined lol.</p><h3 id="Nicole-quarrel-responsibilities"><a href="#Nicole-quarrel-responsibilities" class="headerlink" title="Nicole, quarrel, responsibilities"></a>Nicole, quarrel, responsibilities</h3><blockquote><p>The biggest contributor to discontent in otherwise healthy relationships is an accumulation of unspoken and unclarified expectations.</p></blockquote><p>What 陆屿 said after and, think that was exactly what I got to learn.</p><p>Had a quarrel with nicole earlier this month, remember having this feeling of unfair, getting only a few replies with the messages I sent.</p><p>Ping-ya, Bill and Louie all mentioned about expectation and responsibilities. I only get to control how much I reachout, and have set way too high of an expectation of the responsiveness on my counterparts.</p><p>Jokingly calls Nicole 小公主 sometimes and found it ironic that, she really is one of the most emotionally intelligent person I got to meet this year. There is still much I get to learn on communicating with others.</p><h3 id="Dad-trip-planning-悟道"><a href="#Dad-trip-planning-悟道" class="headerlink" title="Dad, trip planning, 悟道"></a>Dad, trip planning, 悟道</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-11/seattle-trip-spreadsheet.png" alt="placeholder" style=""><span class="image-caption">placeholder</span><p>Borrowed some money from parents for a two week trip to Seattle. When dad asked what my plan is, mind immediately went to how I would spend the money</p><p>After hearing my detailed proposal on how I would spend each dime my dad went</p><blockquote><p>你借钱出去玩是为了把借来的钱给花掉吗 :D?</p></blockquote><p>As a buddist himself, dad talked about the term 修佛 and 悟道, realting that to trip planning, what my goal is being on a trip, and how I should spend the money would come naturally afterwards.</p><p>For me I want me and the people on the trip to bond closer together + get to enjoy a new enviorment in a relaxing way, felt I had much more of a plan coming aftwards.</p><h3 id="Capstone-TA-non-zero-sum-game"><a href="#Capstone-TA-non-zero-sum-game" class="headerlink" title="Capstone TA, non-zero sum game"></a>Capstone TA, non-zero sum game</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-11/bill-back.jpg" alt="After the chat went out for a walk and felt, relived" style=""><span class="image-caption">After the chat went out for a walk and felt, relived</span><p>Bill referred me and another junior as HCI capstone TA candidates for S23, I got offered the position after the interview.</p><p>After a chat with the professor learned there is only one TA spot for the course, and other candidates will be considered only if I reject mine. Knowing that there was another candidate Bill recommended thought ‘anyway I can do better’.</p><p>So yeah, two email threads, a bunch of nodding and a few other ‘how may do this’ after, the SCS department agreed to hire another TA for the course, both of us got to be TAs :D.</p><p>Steve said I am now a puppet master though felt the opposite, I understood the rule of the game and chose to alter it, and leave my counterparts room to make their own choices, I can feel the mature part of myself showing in the process. This blog has been dominated by reflections and learning, felt this time I get to be proud of myself.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Placeholder</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - October 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20221201/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20221201/</id>
    <published>2022-12-01T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:38:51.623Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Nicole-birthday-hiding-intentions"><a href="#Nicole-birthday-hiding-intentions" class="headerlink" title="Nicole, birthday, hiding intentions"></a>Nicole, birthday, hiding intentions</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-10/nicole-birthday.jpg" alt="Happy 21, birthday girl :)" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">Happy 21, birthday girl :)</span><p>A group of friends hosted a surprise for Nicole’s birthday at 2:30 pm, after lunch with Nicole we were standing at the bus stop around 2 pm and suddenly thought</p><p>Wait if I am getting to the same place to surprise nicole, how can I get to the same place without surprising nicole :D?</p><p>And that’s when I realized I was quite bad at lying lol, wasn’t able to find a way to tell Nicole that I am going to the same place when it’s in the exact opposite direction of where I was supposed to head to</p><p>As a kid there was very little cost in speaking our minds in my family, so I guess through time, hiding my intention really did become one of my duller abilities. I would be the kind of guy that asks ‘what do you want for your birthday and just get the gift, not realizing that it’s the feeling of being remembered and cared for that matters more. Nicole mentioned multiple time that ‘it’s just a feeling and Steve simply refers me as ‘研磨间的驴’, guess they do have a point lol.</p><p>More so an observation than a reflection, I understood myself better when I interacted with someone else. I tend to be transparent with my thought, choosing to be silent when I feel insecure, and currently in the process of feeling the more emotional side of things.</p><p>So in the end, jump off the bus a few stops early, ran to the corner and called an uber, told the driver I was too lazy to walk the 5-minute walk and she believed it :D</p><h3 id="Helen-confidence-I-will"><a href="#Helen-confidence-I-will" class="headerlink" title="Helen, confidence, I will"></a>Helen, confidence, I will</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-10/scott-hall.png" alt="Scott Hall where I usually work with Helen" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">Scott Hall where I usually work with Helen</span><p>Helen absolutely hates it when people say ‘I hope’ or ‘I wish’, she mentioned these words meant carelessness and fear of taking responsibility.</p><p>I tend to use these words when I feel uncertain and want to be safe, thinking now, these phrases directly translate to a lack of confidence.</p><p>While I was learning PARA read similar things, when creating a project you should look for a verb that describes done, finalize, submit, making the action transparent and yourself accountable</p><p>The way we present matters just as much as the material itself was I came to, so started using phrases that boost confidence, namely ‘I will’. ‘I will make a plan for the trip’ and ‘I will resolve this bug and push a PR’ in itself gives me more confidence and certainty, alerting me to complete it.</p><p>And I was that ‘people’ at the beginning of the story by the way lol, appreciate the lesson and thought, life really is an ongoing journey.</p><h3 id="Shortcuts-perfecting-the-basics"><a href="#Shortcuts-perfecting-the-basics" class="headerlink" title="Shortcuts, perfecting the basics"></a>Shortcuts, perfecting the basics</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-10/shelly-you.png" alt="part of our app mock ups" style=""><span class="image-caption">part of our app mock ups</span><p>Got a chance to design phone apps and through found that, I went with minimalistic styles because I simply don’t have the basic skills of laying out things differently, I can’t do another style.</p><p>That was just the start beginning lol, after I signed the internship started doing competitive analysis with Jimmy, and disturbingly, I had no idea where to begin to dissect an app knowing that I would be a product manager intern soon, the question marks on Jimmy’s head when I told him I don’t know where to start :’)</p><p>I am a strong believer of ‘half ass with everything you got’, but recently wondered if I’ve taken too many shortcuts to get to where I am today, ignoring the basics that come before the fancy title&#x2F;result.</p><p>An opposite example for me was TAing, every recitation I would list out three key points, and practice saying them in front of a mirror, the most basic part of presentation. Crystal mentioned that I have something called ‘亲和力’, imagined it was through the time that I practiced saying words while being a TA lol.</p><p>Thinking about perfecting the basics, mind went to the dance tutorials on moving legs + shoulders Nicole sent, I will put more emphasis on these starting now.</p><h3 id="Thomas-self-development-accepting-yourself"><a href="#Thomas-self-development-accepting-yourself" class="headerlink" title="Thomas, self development, accepting yourself"></a>Thomas, self development, accepting yourself</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-10/catman-walk.jpg" alt="After the chat went out for a walk and felt, relived" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">After the chat went out for a walk and felt, relived</span><p>Chat with Thomas this month and talked to him about this frustration, knowing that I put heavy effort into self development, yet yielded little results.</p><p>About 20 minutes of rant Thomas just sat and listened, afterwards he talked about his 20s and the dramas he’s being through, summarized into one sentence</p><blockquote><p>You are enough of who you are</p></blockquote><p>And more importantly, surround yourself who also think you are enough.</p><p>I swear that’s not the thing he said lol, he mentioned time as a factor that I missed too, this phrase ‘good thing takes time’, I would get to practice it for a long time before it yields results (like workouts!).</p><p>So combining all together, continue improving myself (for the sake of improving myself), surround myself with people who accept me, and let time do their work.</p><p>I deserve to be loved without doing anything towards it, was one of the takeaways I learned through the conversation. Thomas good luck with your start-up and your relationship, I know things will turn out best for you in the end :)</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Celebrated birthday and learned I can&#39;t hide my thoughts; learned to be more confident with things I say; designed an app and realized I took too many shortcuts in life; felt frustrated by personal growth and learned to love myself.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - September 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20221121/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20221121/</id>
    <published>2022-11-21T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:37:36.223Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Birthday-22-feeling-special"><a href="#Birthday-22-feeling-special" class="headerlink" title="Birthday, 22, feeling special"></a>Birthday, 22, feeling special</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-09/birthday-cake.jpg" alt="Cake for 22" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">Cake for 22</span><p>I was never big on birthdays, not that I don’t like celebrating, this sense of reluctance, being the center of attention? Parties presents and cakes, these tends to excite me much less compared to others.</p><p>That is to say, still felt nice getting surprises though. Remember waking up in the afternoon seen Anita &amp; Elisa’s text with the bolded ‘HAPPY BIRTHDAY SEAN’, this warm and fuzzy feeling that I am on their mind, felt quite special.</p><p>And yes talking about special I did get myself a small slice of cheesecake, Xiaohan insisted it was a pie :’).</p><h3 id="Getting-COVID"><a href="#Getting-COVID" class="headerlink" title="Getting COVID"></a>Getting COVID</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-09/uxa-welcome.jpg" alt="Since I wasn't able to join in person, UXA hosted a virtual welcome" style=""><span class="image-caption">Since I wasn't able to join in person, UXA hosted a virtual welcome</span><p>Started off with a pretty bad sore throat the second week in the afternoon, turned into a fever later into the night. Tested in the morning and yup, I was indeed positive lol.</p><p>First time having COVID so took around two and half weeks to recover, luckily I’ve gotten the booster shots so it really just felt like a mild fever.</p><p>Similar reflection towards birthday, appreciated the amount of care more than anything else. Professors handed me unlimited late days for the assignments I missed, Nicole brought groceries directly to my door, and Helen after sending ‘bitch don’t die’ rush over and dropped off enough Tylenol to take for the rest of my life (thank you all so much lol).</p><p>Thinking now, felt fortunate that no one I knew got COVID in the meantime, felt a sense of guilt&#x2F;unease imagining people around me getting it because of me…</p><h3 id="One-day-I-will-life-as-a-map"><a href="#One-day-I-will-life-as-a-map" class="headerlink" title="One day I will, life as a map"></a>One day I will, life as a map</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-09/duolingo-rejection.png" alt="One of the many rejections that I've got" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">One of the many rejections that I've got</span><blockquote><p>Life is so much more about avoiding the wrong choices than making the right ones</p></blockquote><p>Wrote to myself that life is an infinite game <a href="https://yize.blog/20220920/#Mom-End-of-the-Line">this August</a> and realized I wasn’t following it at all lol. Now in the environment of school, I’ve again dwelling on a past that I can’t alter, worrying about a future I can’t predict.</p><p>Sure I told myself ‘live under the present’ just like <a href="https://yize.blog/20220920/#Mom-End-of-the-Line">this May</a> however, felt less helped as I am way too similar to the people I surround myself with rn, wanting the same thing and constantly comparing.</p><p>桌沿 mentioned life being a map instead of a track, that there is no such thing as the ‘right choice’, as we are all running towards different directions</p><blockquote><p>你我并未站在同一跑道上赛跑，我们遥遥相望，彼此鼓励和祝福，然后继续奔跑在广袤的地图之中、自己的人生道路之上。</p></blockquote><p>In the future think life as an infinite game, and in the present understand that we are running towards different goals, felt that’s the missing puzzle piece that I need.</p><h3 id="Talking-about-myself"><a href="#Talking-about-myself" class="headerlink" title="Talking about myself"></a>Talking about myself</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-09/boston-ook-concert.jpg" alt="Felt nice being tall thanks mom" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">Felt nice being tall thanks mom</span><blockquote><p>不在于你写得是不是“我”，而在于你写的是不是“人”。</p></blockquote><p>Attended a concert at Boston during the weekend with some friends. While chatting with Angela she said</p><blockquote><p>Talking to you doesn’t feel like, talking to you?</p></blockquote><p>As funny as I felt, Anita mentioned the same thing once, I listen, rephrase and then quote other’s experiences in a conversation, avoiding touching myself in the process; the same pattern appears looking back at my blog, I often skip ‘I’s in a sentence, making the writing appear third person.</p><p>I felt, afraid?, talking about my point of view. When in conversations often bring forth the point instead of myself, and in writing I always try to stay objective.</p><p>Hence the reflection, knowing the people that I get to meet in the past few years, I want to be, more emotional almost? Saying more terms like ‘I think’ and ‘I feel’, doing things because I like them now, instead of thinking a year in the future.</p><blockquote><p>It doesn’t matter whether it’s first or third person, people care more about how much they can resonate with the experience you share, if they think you are human, you know.</p></blockquote><p>What Xiaohan said.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Turned 22 and appreciated being treated special, got COVID and spend sometime with myself, tried to retain peace by focus on the present, and learned to be more expressive towards my own thoughts and emotions</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - August 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20220920/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20220920/</id>
    <published>2022-09-20T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:31:12.289Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Grandpa-Empathy"><a href="#Grandpa-Empathy" class="headerlink" title="Grandpa, Empathy"></a>Grandpa, Empathy</h2><img src="../images/oj-2022-08/grandpa-shirt.jpg" alt="In case you didn't know, pink is my grandpa's favorite color." style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">In case you didn't know, pink is my grandpa's favorite color.</span><p>My grandpa has remained the least empathetic person I’ve met.</p><p>Visited him back in 2019, every morning he would slam open the guest bedroom, drag me to the bathroom at 5:30am while yelling</p><blockquote><p>起来啊太阳都晒屁股了</p></blockquote><p>I get up reluctantly, dressing half asleep, take a look outside, and realize the sun is indeed brightly shining</p><p>in the United States of America :’).</p><p>Blunt and abrasive, ironically grandpa is also the most caring person when it comes to me. As he would reenforce every time we chat, ‘if you want to eat something go have it, if you fail the exam fuck the professors, if you need money ask grandpa’ he would say on repeat.</p><p>When little always wanted to be someone like grandpa, however, as time passes by, I am less of the kid back then. I start to notice people around me, their emotions and ways of thinking. Had a chat with Lucia and she described me as someone who is 优柔寡断, taking too long to make decisions.</p><p>I feel comfortable who I am now, though seen the changes, can’t help remembering back as a kid, sitting on his lap, at the balcony eating watermelons, his picture of this simple world:</p><blockquote><p>以后如果有人要是欺负你，你使劲干他就完事了.</p></blockquote><h2 id="Dad-Empathy-Fishing"><a href="#Dad-Empathy-Fishing" class="headerlink" title="Dad, Empathy, Fishing"></a>Dad, Empathy, Fishing</h2><p>Dad taught me two lessons on empathy. The first was ‘treat people the way you wish to be treated’. Remember he taught me this after an intense fight with a classmate back in kindergarten, and found the lesson helpful ever since.</p><p>That is, until I had my failed confession lol, as I was baffled on what I missed, so dad and I sat down, and he taught me the second lesson of his life.</p><p>The story goes like this: My dad, while little, went fishing by himself one day and caught nothing. That night he also got beat up because it turns out, he has used his favorite food (pork belly) as bait and used it all up.</p><blockquote><p>You know [my nickname], sometimes it’s about treating people the way they wish to be treated.</p></blockquote><p>And that’s the story of how I was helped lol, realizing that different people wish to be treated in different ways.</p><h2 id="Mom-End-of-the-Line"><a href="#Mom-End-of-the-Line" class="headerlink" title="Mom, End of the Line"></a>Mom, End of the Line</h2><p>Past couple of days my mom brought back up the infamous phrase</p><blockquote><p>I will finally be free after you graduate from college</p></blockquote><p>While feeling ironic ( because three years ago the sentence was ‘I will finally be free after you graduate from high school’), I also thought, perhaps I had the same mindset?</p><p>As for now my mind set has been, once I find an intern at a bigger tech company, the future of my life will be settled. But clearly that’s not the case lol, I’ve already switched my major twice at college, and my life post-college would only be longer + with more turbulence.</p><p>I wonder if it’s because I set my target too close in the future, hence this feeling that everything will be done once goals are achieved.</p><p>Jimmy taught me to see life as a game, an infinite game, because once you do, you will no longer be blinded by what everyone else is doing right now, and will keep going even after you didn’t hit your milestone.</p><p>Changing the current goal from ‘secure an intern’ to ‘become a better storyteller’, will keep myself updated on how it goes.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Thought about empathy, my grandpa, mom, dad, and myself.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - July 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20220728/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20220728/</id>
    <published>2022-07-28T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:31:34.584Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Life-Updates"><a href="#Life-Updates" class="headerlink" title="Life Updates"></a>Life Updates</h2><h3 id="Dental-Appointment-Sharing-Life"><a href="#Dental-Appointment-Sharing-Life" class="headerlink" title="Dental Appointment, Sharing Life"></a>Dental Appointment, Sharing Life</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-07/dentist.jpg" alt="The doc played waterfall music during the surgery, felt calming & helpful" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">The doc played waterfall music during the surgery, felt calming & helpful</span><p>Went for a dental appointment third week of July, while taking the x-ray the doctor suddenly asked</p><blockquote><p>What’s on your mind?</p></blockquote><p>I was not expecting her to ask that lol. It was my last week in California, a sense of uncertainty was filling my heart. Talked to the doc about the 5 waitlisted classes next semester, people that I lost touch with during the summer, job hunts, post graduation plans, this feeling of, not wishing to sit around, but also unsure where I am heading to.</p><p>The doc, still operating the machine at the time, listened and nodded, letting out a few ‘mhm’ here and there. At the end after a long pause, she slowly let out ‘thanks for sharing, must take you a lot of courage to say these out loud’.</p><p>Felt a sudden sense of relief after hearing that lol, it mattered less whether she resonated with my thoughts, the fact she recognized my effort of saying these, that alone made me feel appreciated and content.</p><p>Wishing to be understood, thought if that’s one hidden goal I always had in mind.</p><p>07-19 update Jacqlyn said the doc was probably just asking how my teeth are I am on my way to jump off a cliff now</p><h3 id="Productivity-Double-Counting"><a href="#Productivity-Double-Counting" class="headerlink" title="Productivity, Double Counting"></a>Productivity, Double Counting</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-07/the-psychology-of-money-mockup.jpg" alt="Book mockup I did, be happy to share the method if you are interested :D" style=""><span class="image-caption">Book mockup I did, be happy to share the method if you are interested :D</span><p>Let’s say you are walking on the street, and suddenly find this clean, crisp $100 sitting in the corner, you are very happy (hopefully?). So you went and bought 50 Big Macs (ate them in one go); an hour later you shopped five Uniqlo &amp; Spy X Family Collab shirts (and threw the receipt immediately). Both these goods cost around $100, and we just gave the same $100 bill two purposes, spending more than what we found.</p><p>Now let’s replace the phrase money with time, and that’s what we call procrastination lol.</p><p>Too often for me, early in the morning I would relax and plan to work afternoon, however by afternoon I choose to relax again instead of work, this cycle on and on.</p><p>Two things helped, first an article about envelopment budgeting:</p><blockquote><p>而每次有新的收入时（不管是固定薪水、稿酬、红包），都先进入「可用预算」，再明确地分配到一个或几个预算信封中，这样可以避免「得到一笔 1000 块的横财，却在五次消费时都认为自己花的是这笔钱」的幻觉。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://sspai.com/post/61367">摆脱超支困境，试试用这套「信封预算法」记账吧</a>.</p><p>This idea of ‘giving each dollar a purpose’ was inspiring, tried doing the same with time. Helen recommended this software Toggltrack, has been very helpful.</p><p>The other, listened to The Psychology of Money again at the airport this week, resonated with this quote</p><blockquote><p>Like everything else worthwhile, successful investing demands a price. But its currency is not dollars and cents. It’s volatility, fear, doubt, uncertainty, and regret- all of which are easy to overlook until you’re dealing with them in real time.</p></blockquote><p>Replace investing with time management, realized I’ve written about this in <a href="https://yize.blog/20220228/#Let-Myself-be-Human-It%E2%80%99s-Okay-to-Feel-Down">allow myself to be human</a>, this thought on facing challenges instead of running away from it.</p><p>Interesting how similar money is to time, both finite, both we wish to maximize its value.</p><h3 id="Procrasination-People-I-Surround-Myself-With"><a href="#Procrasination-People-I-Surround-Myself-With" class="headerlink" title="Procrasination, People I Surround Myself With"></a>Procrasination, People I Surround Myself With</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-07/keffi-doodle.jpg" alt="Placeholder, doodle for a friend’s goldendoodle" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">Placeholder, doodle for a friend’s goldendoodle</span><p>Felt clumsy last week of June, logged a total of 22 productive hours out of 168. Chatted with Nancy and she mentioned this word ‘jaded’, got reminded of 内耗 too.</p><p>Two things helped, first an article:</p><blockquote><p>拖延也许并不是一个时间管理的问题，而是一个情绪管理的问题。可能不是你不想做，恰恰相反，是你想做的太好了。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://landisland.zhubai.love/posts/2160455851511955456">自说自话 - 也许拖延是一个情绪管理问题</a>. Recently realized I find joy&#x2F;support through people I surround myself with, and this pattern seems to appear: I am the most productive when I feel cared, when people around me are happy.</p><p>The second from chatting with mom. Mom mentioned I rarely enjoy the current moment, that day when I was planning out my afternoon, while eating brunch with her.</p><p>There’s this phrase in chinese called ‘逆水行舟’, wonder if I’ve been blinded by it, always wanting for more, forgetting the fact of enjoying the present.</p><p>So stay in touch with others, enjoy the current moment, this is a follow up to <a href="https://yize.blog/20220604/#Workout-Enjoying-the-Current-Moment">the workout story</a>.</p><p>Also linking to the $100 story, there seems to be this weird loop: I tend to use finance articles to help with time management, productivity articles to deal with myself, and self-discovery articles to manage my money lol.</p><h3 id="Communication-Interview"><a href="#Communication-Interview" class="headerlink" title="Communication, Interview"></a>Communication, Interview</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-07/uxa-newsletter-interview.png" alt="As an afterthought, should’ve trust my past experiences a bit more during the interview" style=""><span class="image-caption">As an afterthought, should’ve trust my past experiences a bit more during the interview</span><p>Had an interview with the UXA newsletter team, during the chat, had a flashback to something Nicole said</p><blockquote><p>Talking to you feels like I am in an interview</p></blockquote><p>Funny thing is, she’s not alone lol. Multiple people have brought it up so far this summer.</p><p>Maggie, ‘I need a break from all these follow ups’; Steven, ‘What’s going on with YOUR life Sean :D?’; Xiaohan, ‘In this chat Sean you are gonna talk about you, I am not talking until you do’; Frank, ‘如果提问是掘地你已经在刨我的祖坟了’.</p><p>To my defense, only ask more when I’m interested in the conversation&#x2F;people, this feeling of content getting to know them better. Perhaps I’ve skewed the idea of conversation, as what Ping-Ya said, listening and conveying are two different things, a chat needs both to be kept alive.</p><p>Thinking now, at this moment I would love to share more, it’s simply the <a href="https://yize.blog/20220705/#Learning-connecting-teaching">lack of practice</a>. <a href="https://yize.blog/20220513/#Deep-Convo-Chat-with-Family-Emotional-Granularity">Family conflict</a> has now diminished, I have also <a href="https://yize.blog/20220513/#Failed-Confession">confessed my feelings</a> to people I’ve drawn towards.</p><blockquote><p>所以我没想着彻底改变自己，变得外向啊、善于交谈啊什么的，只是想学一点沟通技巧，总结一点经验，能够和我爱的、我认同的以及爱我的人们相处的更好。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://sspai.com/post/69118">社恐自救：闲聊的话题和技巧</a>. Linking to the dentist story, I just wish to tell better stories, to better convey my thoughts you know.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Talked to a dentist about life, learned time management through finance articles, dealt with 内耗 by focus on the present, started talking about myself more in conversations.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - June 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20220705/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20220705/</id>
    <published>2022-07-05T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:31:45.465Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Life-Updates"><a href="#Life-Updates" class="headerlink" title="Life Updates"></a>Life Updates</h2><h3 id="Cold-Showers-Grit"><a href="#Cold-Showers-Grit" class="headerlink" title="Cold Showers, Grit"></a>Cold Showers, Grit</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-06/cold-shower.png" alt="Placeholder" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">Placeholder</span><p>Started taking cold showers, felt little difference three weeks past.</p><p>First time doing it, remember standing at the tub, slowly turning the knob right, with the temperature drop I immediately started shivering, gasping for air, heart beating more noticeable in the chest, every inch of my skin closing, my body clamped together to trap the lingering heat.</p><p>None of these reactions lingered after a week, though other than being more prone to cold, the shower now felt, normal almost.</p><p>After three weeks, so far no significant up or downside, despite polar opposite views, one end papers indicating healthier body, on the other my mom shouting ‘啊这么多寒气再这么洗下去你肾要没了’ everytime I come out.</p><p>‘Really have to try it yourself before making judgment’ was the biggest takeaway, though it may be more of a mental shift, this sense of, doing something I am afraid of, actively making life less comfortable and actively adapt, Xiaohan mentioned this phrase called ‘grit’.</p><h3 id="Asking-for-Help-Non-Zero-Sum-Game"><a href="#Asking-for-Help-Non-Zero-Sum-Game" class="headerlink" title="Asking for Help, Non Zero Sum Game"></a>Asking for Help, Non Zero Sum Game</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-06/it-takes-two.jpg" alt="'能把双人成行玩成分手厨房，真的只有和你了'" style=""><span class="image-caption">'能把双人成行玩成分手厨房，真的只有和你了'</span><p>Played It Takes Two with Steve, afterwards chatted about life, post college living, job hunt and writing resumes, and that’s when he offered to help.</p><p>As always, first thought immediately goes towards ‘how I am supposed to pay back’. Helping others felt like, a burden to me, knowing that I want to pay it back at some point.</p><p>Said that to Steve and he shrugged, thought for a bit, ‘you can always pay me back later, wasn’t looking for payback in the first place’ he said.</p><p>Nicole said accepting&#x2F;trust may be the best for the person offering too, thought more on making the relationship mutually beneficial, making the cake bigger.</p><h3 id="Curiocity-Kiwi"><a href="#Curiocity-Kiwi" class="headerlink" title="Curiocity, Kiwi"></a>Curiocity, Kiwi</h3><p>Chatting on Xiaohan’s upcoming study abroad, when introducing Shandong Normal University she went ‘why does 师范 translates to normal in english’.</p><p>Searched it up, turns out ‘normal’ was a borrowed word from French, as its first higher education institute was named ‘École Normale Supérieure’, later adapted by the rest of the world.</p><p>Less about the answer, people I met from the university tend to share this, almost child-like curiosity. Nancy took a gap year and learned Crypto, Chen spent weeks experimenting with the same recipes, Elliot coding 4 versions of an exercise before publishing.</p><p>When chatting with others I would sometimes have a voice in my quiet mind, screaming at me to ask follow ups, the smallest details my counterpart said. Perhaps the same gist here, but on things.</p><p>About 3 days later, saw a box of kiwi at the grocery store and searched the name’s origin, apparently kiwi was originated from China, wasn’t until it was exported to New Zealand that it got the name ‘kiwi’, as it’s similar to the kiwi bird on that land.</p><h3 id="Learning-connecting-teaching"><a href="#Learning-connecting-teaching" class="headerlink" title="Learning, connecting, teaching"></a>Learning, connecting, teaching</h3><blockquote><p>有一个很土的词儿叫「不忘初心」，大概也就是这么一个定义：回到你最初的需求，调整一种更合理的方式去为之努力，不要用「改变」来代替「纠正」。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://sspai.com/post/52930">情绪自救：把「自己」从情绪深渊中拯救出来</a>. Not related to the thoughts below, just thought that’s something I would say if this topic ever came up again.</p><p>Was chatting with Nicole about upcoming job hunt, our aspirations, goals in life.</p><blockquote><p>Sometimes im like hm why do i care so much about getting a very good internship is it bc i want to or also other ppl</p></blockquote><p>Via Nicole. Shared similar feelings, but unable to translate them into thoughts. It’s almost like, finding my own car at the parking lot, after getting groceries lol, I have the memory of parking it, though not sure where exactly it’s at.</p><p>Listening is not the same as expressing, wish I could better express my thoughts and feelings. Thinking now, someone that say what’s on their mind, injects emotions and keeps counterparts engaged, people I know have already shown me how.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Taking cold showers and felt little difference, tried to ask for help more, attempt to regain a sense of curiocity at things, and wish to better express thoughts and feelings directly.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - May 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20220604/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20220604/</id>
    <published>2022-06-04T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:32:06.976Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Life-Updates"><a href="#Life-Updates" class="headerlink" title="Life Updates"></a>Life Updates</h2><h3 id="Workout-Enjoying-the-Current-Moment"><a href="#Workout-Enjoying-the-Current-Moment" class="headerlink" title="Workout, Enjoying the Current Moment"></a>Workout, Enjoying the Current Moment</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-05/workout.png" alt="4 weeks :D" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">4 weeks :D</span><p>First two weeks of work out felt fine, though found it significantly more difficult, convincing myself to get up and workout starting the third week. This vicious cycle of, procrastinating and feeling anxious towards it, Helen mentioned this word ‘内耗’.</p><p>Similar trend appeared before and, linking back to cooking <a href="https://yize.blog/20220325/#%E8%B1%86%E8%A7%92%E7%84%96%E9%9D%A2-Work-Life-Balance">豆角焖面</a>, this idea of enjoying the present moment seemed to be the solution.</p><p>Logically it made sense, though still felt this fear within me, shouldn’t I be doing something more productive, something more beneficial to my future?</p><p>Had quite a debate and, the answer I came to was, I really don’t know what the future me would want lol. I assumed that I have all the knowledge, but more often than not, with new things experienced, the direction I head to changes.</p><p>Sure a more fit body would be the end goal, but when attribute the reason to a more vibrant start to my morning, did realize it helped me continue on the trend. Something Nicole has said</p><blockquote><p>Yesterday is history. Tomorrow is a mystery. And today? Today is a gift. That’s why we call it the present</p></blockquote><h3 id="The-Way-You-Present-Empathy"><a href="#The-Way-You-Present-Empathy" class="headerlink" title="The Way You Present, Empathy"></a>The Way You Present, Empathy</h3><blockquote><p>『别人的事情』和『自己的事情』在大脑中的加工方式是不一样的，别人撞墙你也许不仅不疼还会幸灾乐祸，自己擦破皮就龇牙咧嘴了…… 一个弥补的办法在于努力设想自己处于别人的境地，经历别人所经历的事情，感受它们，使它们和你的情绪记忆挂钩。</p></blockquote><p>Back in second grade, dad took a rainy afternoon and taught me dinner etique. It was close to evening when we finished, and while wrapping up, handing him forks on the table, he leaned over, patted me softly on the head and said, ‘you know [my nickname], the best dinner etiquette really is just the one same as your counterpart’.</p><p>And I was quite furious lol, sitting through hour-long lectures only to be told that it would not be useful, I may or maynot have have been upset for that whole day lol.</p><p>Memory long forgotten but, two stories this month that helped me pick this back up.</p><img src="../images/oj-2022-05/rex-golfclub.jpeg" alt="" style=""><p>Rex came back to California and we met up. Instead of a coffee shop, a sandwich place or the library, we met at a golf club at around 7am.</p><img src="../images/oj-2022-05/nicole-facetime.jpg" alt="Nicole if you are reading this I hope you are happy" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">Nicole if you are reading this I hope you are happy</span><p>Had the thought to keep in contact with Nicole, and we chatted on facetime instead of Zoom.</p><p>Although try to maintain contact with many, rarely have this idea of, what my counterpart would want, what would make them enjoy the moment just as much as I do. Thinking more about what dad taught me, perhaps he was trying to teach me to be empathetic, to make them feel comfortable and less about how to use knives and forks?</p><p>Which echoes with the quote, recently started to ask people’s schedule, what their day of life is like, felt like that has helped me better resonate with their mood, how they approach their life.</p><h3 id="Outreach-Spreadsheet-Consistency"><a href="#Outreach-Spreadsheet-Consistency" class="headerlink" title="Outreach, Spreadsheet, Consistency"></a>Outreach, Spreadsheet, Consistency</h3><p>Steve graduated this semester, three years went by in a flash. Were surprised how we were able to keep in contact, despite different college, major, friend group and extracurricular.</p><p>Back in 2021 made a spreadsheet of everyone I know, name, last time of contact, and topics chatted. Been a year since and thought, perhaps consistency really is the key to keep connections. Steve I reach out every 3 month of so, we simply continue on the topics we last left off, and thus the relationship was kept.</p><p>Do similar things to myself, where everyday I’d pick a photo and place it in an album. Would look back at each one at the end of the year, revisit the highlights of each day.</p><img src="../images/oj-2022-05/childhood-pic.jpg" alt="" style=""><p>This was 12-29-2019 on my album, went back to the old house in China and found this, back in Kindergarten, eager to show my mom how far I can throw fruits at a bridge.</p><p>All of these thoughts came from one question, was been asked why I do these in the first place, keeping track of people, recording lives including my own.</p><p>I felt that, highlights of my life has often being moments unrecorded, I simply didn’t realize how precise these moments would be, at that specific time. I wish to keep a consistent track on how my life has being, thus easier to see such trend, and the same with people I surround myself with, similar thoughts in <a href="https://yizeshen7.github.io/blog/20220513/#Synchronous-Response-Sharing-Pictures">Synchronous Response, Sharing Pictures</a>.</p><h3 id="Saying-Goodbye-Ongoing-Journey"><a href="#Saying-Goodbye-Ongoing-Journey" class="headerlink" title="Saying Goodbye, Ongoing Journey"></a>Saying Goodbye, Ongoing Journey</h3><blockquote><p>I just think that something can be good, and also end, and that thing was still good. And it’s okay to be sad that it ended, too. But the idea that anything that ends is automatically less than this hypothetical eternal state of success… I don’t think that’s doing us any good at all.</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://twitter.com/AngieMcKeown/status/1517219883855003648/photo/1">This twitter post</a>.</p><p>Going further on the people spreadsheet, updated the sheet after the semester ended, and realized half of the sheet was now under the ‘inactive’ section, people I no longer contact.</p><p>Logically it was pretty easy to convince myself, I only have so much time and energy in a given day, and wish to prioritize people I wish to be close with.</p><p>However, whenever I move names to the inactive session, do felt a sense of sorrow, mixed in with regret. Felt I have failed to maintain a relationship, failed to establish consistency given time. If I would have done everything correct, would assume the relationship would last, not forever, but a very long time.</p><p>Thus felt grateful after seeing this tweet lol, thinking of life as phases instead of continues, that I don’t have to cling on to everything forever. For people we used to know, perhaps we are still friends, just lighter; we have grown apart, but that doesn’t take away the mark they left on who I am. Thinking now, ‘knowing them’ in a given time is already precise enough, wish them all the best on their ongoing journey.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Started working out and learned again to enjoy the current moment, got reminded of emapthy, thought consistency was the key to maintain relationships and, felt a relationship can be good even if it doesn&#39;t last forever.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - April 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20220513/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20220513/</id>
    <published>2022-05-13T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:36:25.245Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Life-Updates"><a href="#Life-Updates" class="headerlink" title="Life Updates"></a>Life Updates</h2><h3 id="Synchronous-Response-Sharing-Pictures"><a href="#Synchronous-Response-Sharing-Pictures" class="headerlink" title="Synchronous Response, Sharing Pictures"></a>Synchronous Response, Sharing Pictures</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-04/more-pictures.jpg" alt="One example of pictures I took :D" style="width:70%; height:70%;"><span class="image-caption">One example of pictures I took :D</span><p>Wished to focus more on people I surround myself with.</p><p>Originally felt contracting to what I wrote last month, via <a href="https://yizeshen7.github.io/20220325/">Deleting Social Medias</a>, though trying to limit the number of people I care about, putting more effort into people I do care, these two should coexist.</p><p>Along with that, started taking more pictures with the intention of sharing them. Sophie mentioned friends ‘not just care about each other, but also keep each other in the loop’.</p><p>Had questions while attempting it, like, how does one remember to take pictures? Asked that to mom and she said</p><blockquote><p>It’s less about remembering, it’s about having others in mind, people you wish to share you know</p></blockquote><p>…and that was the ‘ah ha’ moment lol, reminded of a tip read about writing better blogs</p><blockquote><p>Pick one obsessive person to write for, and let them be a proxy for the kind of reader you want to attract.</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://perell.com/note/write-for-yourself/">Write for One Person</a>. It became much easier after that, every time I saw something this thought of ‘oh I bet they would like to see this too’ just naturally surfaces to my mind.</p><h3 id="Deep-Convo-Chat-with-Family-Emotional-Granularity"><a href="#Deep-Convo-Chat-with-Family-Emotional-Granularity" class="headerlink" title="Deep Convo, Chat with Family, Emotional Granularity"></a>Deep Convo, Chat with Family, Emotional Granularity</h3><p>Learned the idea of deep convo, updated my family about the past two years of college.</p><p>Ping-Ya abides by three pillars of communication, directness, honesty, and confidentiality, happened to follow the exact opposite when chatting with parents lol, I simply don’t communicate with them.</p><p>So just imagine, after dinner sitting by the kitchen table, lights half dimmed, starting a video call, throwing everything you’ve written on the blog to them in the past two years, and ending it with ‘yup I know that was a lot can we take a selfie together’.</p><img src="../images/oj-2022-04/family-chat.png" alt="...and we took a selfie together"><span class="image-caption">...and we took a selfie together</span><p>Told them about TAing, my gap year, and coming back to school. Overall the conversation was quite chaotic, mixed feelings with me and parents, though do think it was quite valuable.</p><p>For me, was able to label different emotions going through myself during the conversation. Allowing myself to spectate and not fully immersed, I felt more mature perhaps.</p><p>With my parents, realized that it’s less about them intentionally ignoring my needs, they simply don’t know a different way, as mom and dad had flaws in their family growing up.</p><p>It felt ironic because, both me and my parents were holding shields as we don’t understand each other, and it was only until we put it down, that we were truly able to do so.</p><h3 id="Term-Projects-Knowing-When’s-Enough"><a href="#Term-Projects-Knowing-When’s-Enough" class="headerlink" title="Term Projects, Knowing When’s Enough"></a>Term Projects, Knowing When’s Enough</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-04/tp-mentee-projects.png" alt="I am so proud of you all :')"><span class="image-caption">I am so proud of you all :')</span><p>More of an observation, my mentees’ ability to stop and be content with what they have.</p><p>During Term Project season for the course we TA in, I asked every mentee of mine what grades they wish to get. With some calculations many of them said with pleasant surprise</p><blockquote><p>Dude I only need a 80 to keep my current grade (okay not all said dude most were pretty respectful)</p></blockquote><p>And that’s exactly what they did lol. Mind you that most features they did post MVP merely got them any algorithmic points. I was worried, but then my garding partner, first thing after seen live demos from my mentees</p><blockquote><p>Damn your mentees all look so happy</p></blockquote><p>And I was like, yeah that’s true, grades was never their priority.</p><p>My mentees were the perfect example of <a href="https://mindingourway.com/half-assing-it-with-everything-youve-got/">Half-assing it with everything you’ve got</a>, they know how to reach their desired goal with no wasted motion.</p><p>And for me, grades was the single metric that I valued, when there are other factors that’s not on the grading rubric, things like happiness and passion. They reached their grade goal, felt satisfied with what they had, and prioritized on other metrics they have on the project.</p><p>In my final thank you email I wrote</p><blockquote><p>Thanks for hand holding me through wordle basics, showing me the possibility of getting an electric skateboard, reaching out to me on completely none 112 updates, citing tuna salad recipes, and teaching me to feel content with what we have, instead of what could have being :D.</p></blockquote><p>Happiness is the difference between what you have, and your definition of enough. Thought I was supposed to be the one that guided their path, turns out I was the one that learned the most from these lovely people lol.</p><h3 id="Failed-Confession"><a href="#Failed-Confession" class="headerlink" title="Failed Confession"></a>Failed Confession</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-04/failed-confession.jpg" alt="placeholder" style="width:70%; height:70%;"><span class="image-caption">placeholder</span><p>Realized there aren’t much more to share, I have mentioned most things I learned above.</p><p>Family chat, synchronous response, and TP season were more on what I did, failed confessions felt like the reason why I did them. Through the failed confession I learned the power of direct communication, this wish to have others on my mind, and overall, be satisfied with how the relationship has evolved.</p><p>Questions still lingers in my head though, I am confused on how to approach this new relationship, unsure about my next step. Asked Thomas and he said</p><blockquote><p>There isn’t a canonical answer for a question this diverse, …willing to discover and experience how complex life is together, that’s my definition of an intimate relationship</p></blockquote><p>Be willing to commit, express and grow with my counterpart, perhaps that’s what I wish to work on next.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Been politely rejected after a confession (and somehow liked the person even more), made a plan to keep friends more in the loop, updated parents on the past two years of collge, learned how to be satisfied with what you have from my TP mentees</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - March 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20220325/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20220325/</id>
    <published>2022-03-25T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:32:40.160Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>March felt longer as we got a full week off for spring break, however, the second wave of midterms are approaching…</p><h2 id="Life-Updates"><a href="#Life-Updates" class="headerlink" title="Life Updates"></a>Life Updates</h2><h3 id="豆角焖面-Work-Life-Balance"><a href="#豆角焖面-Work-Life-Balance" class="headerlink" title="豆角焖面, Work Life Balance"></a>豆角焖面, Work Life Balance</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-03/garlic-noodle.jpg" alt="" style="width:70%; height:70%;"><p>Instead of view errands as task to complete, tried to see these as a time to relax.</p><p>Followed reciept from <a href="https://sspai.com/prime/story/vol01-lazy-cooking">少数派</a>, attempted 豆角焖面. Cooking meals, compare to ‘rewarding experience with direct beneftis’ back in December 2021, think ‘an experience that allows me to enjoy the current moment’ now became a more accurate definition.</p><p><del>Totallly not because the dish turned out much saltier than expected.</del></p><p>Heard about ‘cabbage cutting meditation’ eariler this month, where one would try to meditating during repeating, simple tasks.</p><blockquote><p>比如这个「卷心菜切丝冥想」。没空做菜的时候，超市里也能买到很多方便的切好丝的净菜，虽然节省了很多时间，但也不免可惜，因为「给卷心菜切丝可是绝佳的冥想时间呢」。关键点：不要觉得麻烦而想着赶紧切完了事，卷心菜切一切最多几分钟不是吗。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://mio.hedwig.pub/i/shun-jian-ji-yi-13-juan-xin-cai-qie-si-ming-xiang">瞬间记忆 - 卷心菜切丝冥想</a>.</p><p>Less about meditation, felt the act of cooking, although less productive, was a nice break from the busy schoo llife. Flipping porks from side to side, sprinkle salt here and there, for a moment I get to forget about assignment dues, projects coming up.</p><p>Relating back to the <a href="https://yize.blog/20220127/#Grabbed-Coffee-with-Ex-TA-Talked-about-Work-Life-Balance">chat with the ex TA</a> on work life balance, January 2022, thought our university taught us how to work, however, still much for us to discover on how to live a healthy, happy life.</p><p>As a side note, raw garlic with noodle really is something else, would highly recommend :’).</p><h3 id="Brouge-Trainers-Enjoying-the-Jounrey"><a href="#Brouge-Trainers-Enjoying-the-Jounrey" class="headerlink" title="Brouge, Trainers, Enjoying the Jounrey"></a>Brouge, Trainers, Enjoying the Jounrey</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-03/brouge.png" alt="The beauty of rougelike games"><span class="image-caption">The beauty of rougelike games</span><p>Was a bit torn between destination and jounrey, which I should prioritize.</p><p>One TA recommended Brouge, a 2MB rougelike game, where players try to pass 26 randomly generated floors, gathering loot and fighting monsters.</p><p>Spend 2 hours playing it during spring break, got hard stuck at around level 8, and decided to beat the game with trainer.</p><p>Embarassing to admit, ever since I got to learn C and how to manipulate bit values, the enjoyment I obtained from games seems to have faded away. It almost felt like I was more powerful when little, spending days battling a side quest boss, and that sense of fulfillment when I finally defeat the obstacles.</p><blockquote><p>幸福不该是悬在终点处的奖赏，它只是道路中偶然乍现的光亮。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://landisland.zhubai.love/posts/2117107059852955648">自说自话 - 了解自己的能力圈</a>, they mentioned about this notion of, the struggles in life is the life itself.</p><p>Time and joy seems to be on two sides of a balance, I only get to choose one at a time. Now that I have focused on the goal, on beating the game, felt I put less emphasis on the jounrey?</p><p>Thought about into the breach, last game I remember playing before coming to college, wish to allocate a day in the summer playing the game, try out a different side of the balance.</p><h3 id="HCI-Application-TA-Feedback-The-Best-Way-To-Be-a-Genius"><a href="#HCI-Application-TA-Feedback-The-Best-Way-To-Be-a-Genius" class="headerlink" title="HCI Application, TA Feedback, The Best Way To Be a Genius"></a>HCI Application, TA Feedback, The Best Way To Be a Genius</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-03/major-application.jpg" alt="Ironically at the time that I am writing this, I still don't know if I got in or not" style="width:70%; height:70%;"><span class="image-caption">Ironically at the time that I am writing this, I still don't know if I got in or not</span><p>As what my grandparents say, ‘台上一分钟，台下十年功’, found it more and more resonating.</p><p>Applied to an additional major last week. While organizing the application portfolio, had this feeling of, ‘wow I have done quite a few things in previous years’.</p><p>Similar thoughts when gotten TA feedbacks two days ago, comments such as ‘explains problem throughly’ and ‘makes it easy to ask questions’.</p><p>This sense of pride and content, instead of contributing it to talent, realized these were true because I have done these longer. For portfolio, I had an extra year of school, thus more projects to showcase. For TA, have 2 semesters of experience already, practicing how I can better explain (the same) problem sets.</p><blockquote><p>那有没有让自己变成天才的方法？James Clear 提供了一个：<br>第一步，围绕一个主题阅读和思考几年；第二步，记录这个过程的所有想法 ── 大部分都会很普通；第三步，回顾你的想法，删掉所有普通的；第四步，打磨和分享其中最好的；第五步，最终看起来像个天才。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://weichen.zhubai.love/posts/2118068912888360960">生活奇旅 - 幻觉</a>, this illusion of being a genius. Moving away from myself, people I see on social medias, it’s simple to category them as gifted, but thinking now, I am more curious on how they got there.</p><h3 id="Deleting-Social-Medias"><a href="#Deleting-Social-Medias" class="headerlink" title="Deleting Social Medias"></a>Deleting Social Medias</h3><p>It has being just about 90 days since I uninstalled Instagram, Facebook and WeChat moments, felt peace of mind.</p><p>The past year social media brought to me more harm than good. Fear of missing out, would constantly refresh my feeed, getting distracted on current task.</p><p>Realized later that, I geniutely care little on other’s life, and for those who I care, it was quite easy to get updated through other means, chatting in person, reachout through emails&#x2F;messages etc.</p><p>Similar point of view appeared in <a href="https://landisland.zhubai.love/posts/2109493451027390464">自说自话 - 你要走自己的路，也要允许他人走在自己的路上</a>, this notion of ‘my life is already full enough, no need to enrich it with other’s moment and snapshots’, feels nice that I get to align my thoughts and action.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Made 豆角焖面 and enjoyed making the meal, realized I should prioritize jounrey over result, thought about the easiest way to be smart (practice and record), thoughts on moving away from Instagram, Facebook and WeChat moments</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - Feburary 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20220228/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20220228/</id>
    <published>2022-02-28T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:32:51.980Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Forgot that Feburary has only 28 days lol, flew by faster than usual it seemed like.</p><h2 id="Life-Updates"><a href="#Life-Updates" class="headerlink" title="Life Updates"></a>Life Updates</h2><h3 id="Fire-Alarm"><a href="#Fire-Alarm" class="headerlink" title="Fire Alarm"></a>Fire Alarm</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-02/fire-alarm.jpg" alt="" style="width:70%; height:70%;"><p>Thought what I would miss the most, while standing outside at 2am in the cold, found it diffult to came up an answer.</p><p>Woken by a sharp siren early in the morning, ‘An emerency has being reported, please stay calm and evacuate to the closest shelter area’. Walked downstairs, fire trucks came, after around half an hour we got informed it was a false alarm.</p><p>Less about the event, when heard the siren was originally sound asleep, felt, quite vunlerable and this fear of being dead slided in, remember heart rate went up, arm and leg stiffened, mind going blank and all stimulates rushing in, unable to process them one by one.</p><p>As it turnes out, someone left a towel at the sauna coal space, the towel caught on fire and the alarm went off for the whole building lol.</p><h3 id="Let-Myself-be-Human-It’s-Okay-to-Feel-Down"><a href="#Let-Myself-be-Human-It’s-Okay-to-Feel-Down" class="headerlink" title="Let Myself be Human, It’s Okay to Feel Down"></a>Let Myself be Human, It’s Okay to Feel Down</h3><p>Tends to get swamped by work at around week 6 to 7 during a semester, with midterms pileing up, extracurricular ramping up in speed.</p><p>This semester specifically, felt less motivated then usual, had a hard time keeping a jounral, not to mention waking up at 6am every morning.</p><p>Though read this article</p><blockquote><p>似乎自己从睁眼开始一天都精力充沛才是健康的。可能也是一种社会规训的结果，永远进步，永远螺旋向上。但其实这不是人类真实的状态啊。人是会累的，人是有情绪的，我们是可以低落的。允许自己有这样的情绪，并且不过度解读，或许是保持平衡的方法。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://sirius.zhubai.love/posts/2101877868530454528" target="_blank">吾栖之地 - 是可以低落的</a>. Thought that, instead of not feeling down, perhaps it’s better to find activities to help get out of this state?</p><p>And on another article</p><blockquote><p>… 情绪可以带着我们走，那我们能不能带着情绪走？</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>有人会健身 2 小时，有人会睡觉，有人会读书，有人会看综艺节目，有人会发呆。我会背 85 个单词。大家都有某种办法，来应对情绪不好的时刻。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://elizen.zhubai.love/posts/2108083783668178944" target="_blank">叁拾一周</a>. Have started baking a bit more as spring break approaches, wish to explore more.</p><h3 id="Grandpa-天天乐-and-Staying-Happy"><a href="#Grandpa-天天乐-and-Staying-Happy" class="headerlink" title="Grandpa, 天天乐, and Staying Happy"></a>Grandpa, 天天乐, and Staying Happy</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-02/calligraphy.jpeg" alt="" style="width:70%; height:70%;"><p>Grandpa changed his pen name to 天天乐, found out two weeks ago during our video chat.</p><p>As he turned 80 last year, grandpa’s vision of life solidified even more, as he attempts to teach me every single we call:</p><blockquote><p>身体第一，学业第二，有空多去交交朋友。</p></blockquote><p>There nothing more important than ‘stay healthy and be happy’ as he state, linking to his new pen name, which translate quite literally to ‘happy everyday’.</p><p>Although I laughed at the new name, do agree. For both me and grandpa, a well being enable us to explore so much more, and being happy brings a positive impact to people we surround ourselves with.</p><p>On how to achieve that state, here is another list that grandpa ask everytime we chat:</p><blockquote><p>Have you had dinner yet<br>Has anyone being bullying you at school<br>Come back and pay a visit ;-;</p></blockquote><p>Answers for these have being consistent ever since start of the pandemic, but this doesn’t stop grandpa from asking. He would nod his head in approval when hearing the first answer, give a good smile hearing the second, and twist his face in disappointment coming to third.</p><p>Saw an article on the benefits of living past 30, as the seemingly infinite path ahead slowly converges</p><blockquote><p>年过三十的好处是，再也不用对未来权衡利弊了。终于开始可以不计得失地面对想走的那条路。哪怕道路幽深，野草荒芜，看不清前路。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="http://lillianwho.com/post/30+%E7%9A%84%E5%A5%BD%E5%A4%84/" target="_blank">喜于微 - 30+的好处</a>. Wish I can live like grandpa one day.</p><h3 id="Empathy-Sympathy-and-Compassion-Seek-First-to-Understand"><a href="#Empathy-Sympathy-and-Compassion-Seek-First-to-Understand" class="headerlink" title="Empathy, Sympathy and Compassion, Seek First to Understand"></a>Empathy, Sympathy and Compassion, Seek First to Understand</h3><blockquote><p>Empathy: 理智上理解他人的情感或情绪状态。<br>Sympathy: 理智上理解他人的情感状态，并且可以分享他人的情感状态。比如，别人伤心，你也跟着一起伤心。<br>Compassion: 理智上理解他人的情感状态，可以分享他人的情感状态，并有向帮助他人的欲望。比如，一位朋友听到我失恋的故事时，越想越气，特别想替我打电话骂前任一顿。</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://laixin.one/lx30-understanding-empathy-sympathy-compassion/" target="_blank">林中来信 - 理解与同情</a>. Felt that, when people reach for help, they aren’t always looking to resolve the issue from talking to me.</p><p>Rather of understanding emotions, I tend to take actions. When one say their throat hurts I went to CVS and got them cough drops the next day, and when one say they feel stressed as they have no time for lunch I get them meal replacement.</p><p>Relized this pragmatic approach I learned directly from my parents, I’ve never thought there would be a, different approach.</p><p>Back in 2020 there was a time I did bad on one exam, drag myself downstairs and told my mom about it. Washing dishes at the time, recall mom slammed the pot that at the sink, water splashing out, asked not to talk on these kinds of things anymore, she seemed, quite frustrated and vulenerable.</p><p>Mother saw my ask for empathy as compassion, there was little she can help with regarding an exam on web development. On the same end, me, took this directly as the way I can help others.</p><blockquote><p>His experience may have impacted his views, When people talk to you, they are not talking about their views, but their pains.</p></blockquote><p>Via <a href="https://via.zhubai.love/posts/2101188043968040960" target="_blank">事不过三 - 阅读碎片</a>.</p><h2 id="Reading-List"><a href="#Reading-List" class="headerlink" title="Reading List"></a>Reading List</h2><ul><li><a href="https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/19698994">如何活着：欲望、外界、标签、天才、时间、人生目标和经历</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Woke up by the fire alarm and panicked, tried to let myself feel negative emotions, talked with grandpa and how to be positive (stay simple), learned a bit about empathy, sympathy and compassion</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - January 2022</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20220127/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20220127/</id>
    <published>2022-01-27T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:32:59.850Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>School has started for us and everything was, as busy as expected? Happy that I still get some time to sit back and reflect though : D.</p><h2 id="Life-Updates"><a href="#Life-Updates" class="headerlink" title="Life Updates"></a>Life Updates</h2><h3 id="Grocery-Shopping"><a href="#Grocery-Shopping" class="headerlink" title="Grocery Shopping"></a>Grocery Shopping</h3><img src="../images/oj-2022-01/grocery-list.jpg" alt="" style="width:70%; height:70%;"><p>Instead of following a shopping list, grab what we need, checkout and go, my roommate likes to go visit every aisles in the shop, look through each item on the rack and think, ‘how useful would this be if I have it in the kitchen&#x2F;fridge this week’.</p><p>Pervious thought this as time consuming and unproductive, browsing with no purpose. Though knowing that we are in a store, why the hurry?</p><p>Felt I tend to set my eye too focused on the result, and forgot about the journey on how I get there.</p><p>It took more time yes, though with the time we spent at the shop, we got time to chat topics that doesn’t exist in dorm rooms, share the joy finding unexpected things.</p><p>As for last week it was Trader Joe’s ‘Asian Dipping Sause’, turned out to it was just vinegar lol.</p><h3 id="How-to-Not-Die-Alone-A-More-Intentional-Life"><a href="#How-to-Not-Die-Alone-A-More-Intentional-Life" class="headerlink" title="How to Not Die Alone, A More Intentional Life"></a>How to Not Die Alone, A More Intentional Life</h3><p>Spent sometime during winter break, finsihed the book on the flight getting back to campus.</p><p>‘Making life more intentional’ was the part I resonate the most, not just being more proactive on finding a relationship, but making you and the counterpart on the same page, choosing an relationship, instead of sliding into it.</p><p>Now there are more freedom for me to choose, who I get to spent time with, what I wish to do, when I want to do them. Given that, thought I can be more proactive&#x2F;intentional, be more informed when making a choice.</p><p>The book was quite an enjoyable read, most of the lesson I would see myself using 10+ years from now lol.</p><h3 id="Information-System-Adimission-Making-Peace-with-Parents"><a href="#Information-System-Adimission-Making-Peace-with-Parents" class="headerlink" title="Information System Adimission, Making Peace with Parents"></a>Information System Adimission, Making Peace with Parents</h3><p>Told my parents about getting adimitted into Information Systems, news I held back from August 2020.</p><p>Found it diffcult opening up to my parents, they are the types of person who tends to be raw and direct, many instances when talking with them, have this feeling of torn and reluctance, it’s almost like, peeling band aid from a fresh cut?</p><p>Though recently finished <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36072.The_7_Habits_of_Highly_Effective_People" target="_blank">The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People</a>, from the book:</p><blockquote><p>Between stimulus and response there is a space. In that space is our power to choose our response. In our response lies our growth and our freedom.</p></blockquote><p>Similar point brought out in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VZcfPGKwt-I" target="_blank">The Boy, The Mole, The Fox and the Horse</a>:</p><blockquote><p>One of our greatest freedom is how we react to things.</p></blockquote><p>When my talking with my parents now I thought to myself, ‘how do I want to feel’, and I wish to be at peace, I wish they can be as well.</p><h3 id="Grabbed-Coffee-with-Ex-TA-Talked-about-Work-Life-Balance"><a href="#Grabbed-Coffee-with-Ex-TA-Talked-about-Work-Life-Balance" class="headerlink" title="Grabbed Coffee with Ex-TA, Talked about Work-Life Balance"></a>Grabbed Coffee with Ex-TA, Talked about Work-Life Balance</h3><p>Went out and grabbed some coffee with an ex-TA, who is graduating this semester. During the chat she mentioned what made her chose a start up over bigger industries, her view on work life balance</p><p>Previously thought work life balance can only be achieved when you are successful, and I was no where near to be, especailly after several rounds of interview rejections.</p><p>To the ex-TA, it’s less about how successful one is, more on, what kind of life she wish to be in. Although soon to be a graduate, she still wish to meet like minded people, work at a slower paced enviroment. To her, start up is more like the continuation of school, allowing her to explore her options, before coming into a commitment.</p><p>Reminded of this saying, ‘life path is an oepn field, not a tunnel’, if I’ve been too focused on one path that everyone else is walking on.</p><h2 id="Things-I’ve-Read"><a href="#Things-I’ve-Read" class="headerlink" title="Things I’ve Read"></a>Things I’ve Read</h2><ul><li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/54304221-how-to-not-die-alone" target="_blank">How to Not Die Along</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VZcfPGKwt-I" target="_blank">The Boy, The Mole, The Fox and the Horse</a></li><li><a href="https://perell.com/essay/against-3x-speed/" target="_blank">Against 3X Speed</a></li><li><a href="https://mindingourway.com/half-assing-it-with-everything-youve-got/" target="_blank">Half ass it with everything you’ve got</a></li><li><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/guides/smarterliving/how-to-be-a-better-friend" target="_blank">How to Be a Better Friend</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Learned a different way to shop groceries, thought about dating, talked to parents about Information System, took some advice on work life balance from an ex-TA</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ongoing Journey - December 2021</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20211229/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20211229/</id>
    <published>2021-12-29T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T22:33:25.256Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Long time no see lol, this semester has being quite busy though, as mentioned before, wish to use this site more as a public journal to help process my thoughts. Thoughts can’t really be processed if I draw nothing down so, planning on trying something different.</p><p>Currently thinking about a monthly update on life and things I found intersting, will see how it goes :D.</p><h2 id="Life-Updates"><a href="#Life-Updates" class="headerlink" title="Life Updates"></a>Life Updates</h2><h3 id="Baking"><a href="#Baking" class="headerlink" title="Baking"></a>Baking</h3><img src="../images/oj-2021-12/banana-bread.jpg" alt="Banana bread :D" style="width:70%; height:70%;"><span class="image-caption">Banana bread :D</span><p>Inspried by my roommate, started baking at around second half of the semester. Quoting directly from him, baking is a quite an ‘rewarding experience with direct benefits’, it’s nice to have something for you to enjoy right after a long learning process.</p><p>At this point have tried chocolate chip cookies and banana cupcakes, wish to learn how to make an actual cakes one day, and perhaps more if I have the time.</p><h3 id="TP-Showcase"><a href="#TP-Showcase" class="headerlink" title="TP Showcase"></a>TP Showcase</h3><img src="../images/oj-2021-12/tp-showcase.jpg" alt="First in-person showcase in about a year and half" style=""><span class="image-caption">First in-person showcase in about a year and half</span><p>Joined an in person 15-112 TP showcase! Got reminded on how much I miss interacting people face to face, was able to see, hear, and interact with everyone all at the same time, their emotions, laughers, feels nice to be back in school :).</p><h3 id="Hikes"><a href="#Hikes" class="headerlink" title="Hikes"></a>Hikes</h3><img src="../images/oj-2021-12/hike.jpg" alt="picture taken from one of the hiking trials" style=""><span class="image-caption">picture taken from one of the hiking trials</span><p>Rarely considered myself an outdoor person, though did start to enjoy hikes more and more, less about the walk itself, more on things I do while on walking I would say?</p><p>I get to listen to audiobooks and podcasts, sometimes listening to musics and even sing along lol, feels almost like I am the only person in this world.</p><p>It’s a good break from whatever I am doing, spent some time with myself and enjoy the sunny weather out in So Cal :).</p><h3 id="双拼"><a href="#双拼" class="headerlink" title="双拼"></a>双拼</h3><img src="../images/oj-2021-12/dual-spell.png" alt="" style=""><p>Learned a bit about <a href="https://www.flypy.com/" target="_blank">小鹤双拼</a>, a chinese input system that focus on 声母 and 韵母.</p><p>Have this tendency to overthink, make things appear harder than they look, and then just not start on them all together.</p><p>So this time blocked out sometime and forced myself to practice it, and it’s being about a week at this point, would say both the input system and time blocking has been quite useful.</p><h3 id="LoR"><a href="#LoR" class="headerlink" title="LoR"></a>LoR</h3><img src="../images/oj-2021-12s/lor.png" alt="" style=""><p>Picked up Legend of Runterra and got 7 wins in its expidition mode.</p><p>One nice thing about being on break is that, I finally get to play games every now and then, and with how poor I am with games (Iron II in League of Legend and Angry Chicken in Hearthstone), was pretty proud of myself on getting to this point :].</p><p>Felt like a big part of my enjoyment on games this break was that, I tried to find joy in games even when I might not be the best gamer. Games like Project Zomboid, Astronarch, or just lower the diffculty of the game in general.</p><h2 id="Reads"><a href="#Reads" class="headerlink" title="Reads"></a>Reads</h2><ul><li><a href="https://cmu.zoom.us/rec/play/OSCx2jjByvqt3sLpFmqKBgafdC2oEvb8mfGeDlpSTLfZhT1VQNuZ9m8_Q-Q9rp9Y3L6fivz83n7fHsOx.3ZaHp8urIwbt4EHK?continueMode=true&_x_zm_rtaid=A4Qkz_r1Qzal0Tpc9dAIgA.1639441955360.d33fc983f4ad123530fb12c1deb80641&_x_zm_rhtaid=719" target="_blank">Parting Thoughts</a> (uy6Z^vnS) from professor Raja</li><li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36576608-flowers-for-algernon" target="_blank">Flower of Algernon</a></li><li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36072.The_7_Habits_of_Highly_Effective_People?ac=1&from_search=true&qid=MGRj7qaPMP&rank=1" target="_blank">The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People</a></li></ul><h2 id="Watched"><a href="#Watched" class="headerlink" title="Watched"></a>Watched</h2><ul><li><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1870479/" target="_blank">The Newsroom</a>, season 1-3</li><li><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0412142/" target="_blank">House M.D.</a>, season 1</li><li><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt14979052/" target="_blank">Happiness</a></li><li><a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1wv411J7hp?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0" target="_blank">培泰红法则</a> by 整天摸鱼的三日坊主</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Started baking with roommates, discovered 小鹤双拼, joined first in person TP showcase, hiked up a hill and felt at peace, complete 7 wins at LoR expidition mode</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Capsule Wardrobe</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20210614/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20210614/</id>
    <published>2021-06-14T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-15T04:35:25.061Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Heard about the idea of capsule wardrobe when I started using Notion, going to draw down some thoughts there. As a quick note that, there are many tutorials&#x2F;guides regarding capsule wardrobes on the web, simply search ‘capsule wardrobe’ or ‘capsule wardrobe notion&#x2F;excel’, you should be able to find some informative ones.</p><img src="../images/2021-06-14/capsule-wardrobe-overview.png" alt="What the closet looks like now" style=""><span class="image-caption">What the closet looks like now</span><p>On Notion I tried to categorize clothings in coloumns,</p><ul><li>Item: usually named as primary cateogry - secondary category - color</li><li>Status: if I am using it right now, idle, or no longer in use</li><li>Brand: brand of the cloth</li><li>Time: keeps track of the condition of the cloth</li><li>Season: when&#x2F;what season to wear</li><li>Type: useful for filtering through items</li></ul><img src="../images/2021-06-14/capsule-wardrobe-content.png" alt="" style=""><p>In Notion you are allowed to create a secondary page inside of an item, where you can expand more in detail:</p><ul><li>Name | Size | Color | Price: helps to find the tiem on the website again</li><li>Laundry | Fabric: how I should take care of the product</li><li>Notes: tried to use it to draw down thoughts about the cloth, how much I enjoyed wearing it, helps me make a better decision if I ever have to purchases similar items again</li></ul><img src="../images/2021-06-14/capsule-wardrobe-filter.png" alt="" style=""><p>You can also filter, group and sort items similar to an excel spreadsheet :).</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Heard about the idea of capsule wardrobe when I started using Notion, Notion is pretty nice for organizing things, digital wardrobe is quirky but, suprisingly helpful.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why Not [Insert Popular Platform]?</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20210517/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20210517/</id>
    <published>2021-05-17T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-15T04:34:50.443Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="../images/2021-05-17/milky-sunday.png" alt="One of the blog account that I follow on WeChat :D" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">One of the blog account that I follow on WeChat :D</span><p>Asked myself this quesitons a few times as well, why not just post these on a WeChat offical account, Medium page, or even easier, stories on my Instagram. To be honest, I am still not sure, and would agree how mature these platforms are compare to this, how many more people I may be able to reach.</p><p>Though thinking now, perhaps I chose the flexibility&#x2F;freedom over most things? On this site I get to post anything, images, videos, short&#x2F;long paragraphs, even a google map if I really feel like it. Realizing that I tend to change as time progresses, having a site that can synchronusly adapt to who I am, feel this would be a better fit for the purpose on recording my life in the coming years (if I have that much time that is :’) ).</p><p>Along with that, felt some kind of pressure when attempting to post on WeChat&#x2F;Instagrams, this thought of wanting to make posts I sent well polished. Here I simply do whatever I wish, without thinking about audience of these post, and how they would react towards it. Want this site to be a place to record&#x2F;express myself, and less about interactions that might come after.</p><p>With that being said though, am not against posting things on social medias. I followed a few blog-like acount on WeChat and Medium, and have enjoyed them very much. Knowing that it’s more about on what you send, less on where you sent these, still in this early stage of exploring options, so wouldn’t be surprised if I change my mind later in the future. Nonetheless, formulating my ideas into words, record my life without worries, these are goals I don’t wish to change, no matter which platform I ended up using :).</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">I enjoy Hexo&#39;s customizability, and wish to force myself to get started, learning that nothing will be perfect, but I can make it better through iterations.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Figma Vector Network</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20210505/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20210505/</id>
    <published>2021-05-05T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-15T04:29:54.381Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The UX desginer at my intern introduced me to vector networks in Figma, a tool to create smooth curves without drawing them myself. Had quite some fun playing around lol.</p><img src="../images/2021-05-05/cat-dog.png" alt="Still not sure how I ended up with a dog when trying mimic this cat but" style=""><span class="image-caption">Still not sure how I ended up with a dog when trying mimic this cat but</span><img src="../images/2021-05-05/selfie-pentool.png" alt="That's me lol" style=""><span class="image-caption">That's me lol</span><p>The hardest part while doing these was determining where the line should curve, and by how much. Often an extra nodes would make the curve overly sharp to fit the original image, and too little nodes makes the line fits less well with the sample image.</p><p>I did have fun making these though, and felt like, the mere attempt of me trying to re draw these, was something I wish to record here.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Something new I discovered in Figma, had quite some fun playing with it, although the result is, entertaining at best lol</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Camping at Lake Perris</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20210322/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20210322/</id>
    <published>2021-03-22T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-15T04:45:31.162Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="../images/2021-03-22/lake-perris-camping.jpg" alt="From right to left: Steven, Steve, me" style=""><span class="image-caption">From right to left: Steven, Steve, me</span><p>Met Steve back in highschool, and somehow kept in touch since then. In early March finished one of his recommendation called ‘Yuru Camp’, and were talking about how cool it would be, if we could go and camp out for a night or two. As a doer himself, a days later I was informed that he is going out camping, and if I wish to join.</p><p>Of course I said yes lol, haven’t being outside since April last year, already forgot what the sun looked like :’). About a week later, I was picked up by his friend Steven, and went on this two day and one night camping trip :D.</p><p>The trip was very nice, we had hot pot on the first night we got there, took a hike half way around the lake, and played Call of Cthulhu before we went to bed.</p><p>Thinking back, I didn’t remember anything specific from the trip, just thought it was a great time talking with them both, and was a relaxing break from everything going on in my gap semester.</p><p>Steve and Steven were no doubt some of the more successful students I met, EECE in UCB, interned at Intel, Amazon, and Apple, great multi-taskers with passions towards almost everything. Nonetheless, found myself enjoying other sides of them, game enthusiasts, anime lovers, and experts in Cthulhu mythos. Interacting with them made me rethink how I should balance between school and life, how I can enjoy my time during school, while learning something new :).</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Camping with Steven and Steven, although doesn&#39;t remember specific moment of the trip, this sense of warmth, of not needing to worry about things coming up, of living under the current moment.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Teaching Assistant and Everything Else</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20201210/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20201210/</id>
    <published>2020-12-10T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-15T04:28:05.140Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before admitted as a TA, one very kind TA reached out through email, asked if there was anything I wish to know on being a teaching assitant. Back then never had the courage to ask, and before I ever had the chance to do so, I became a teaching assitance myself :’). Realizing that being a TA is a lot more than just teaching recitations, thought I would record some thoughts here.</p><h2 id="Grading"><a href="#Grading" class="headerlink" title="Grading"></a>Grading</h2><img src="../images/2020-12-10/ta-grading.png" alt="A snippet of how the TA OHQ works" style=""><span class="image-caption">A snippet of how the TA OHQ works</span><p>In the course we TAed, all quizes were graded the day students took them, although have fully expected this coming in as a TA, was surprsied how much we interact while grading.</p><p>We would share how a student struggles to write for loops but overcame all obstacles and derived to the right solution, ask about each other’s day, laugh at funny drawings student put on paper, when they finished early or have given up on a problem entirely lol.</p><p>Thought grading quizzes would be time consuming and hectic, which turned out to be true, but on the other hand, working with a group of peoeple towards the same goal, laugh&#x2F;sturggle together along the way, felt that was one thing that made these Tuesday night more attractive than what it could have being.</p><h2 id="Hackathon"><a href="#Hackathon" class="headerlink" title="Hackathon"></a>Hackathon</h2><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ThNc4N_0Bo8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>We host a hackathon every semester, where students get to create an applicaiton using what they learned, with up to 3 other members, within 24 hours. That semester I was in charge of making a hype video for the event that semester, and yeah, I have never really edit a hype video before :’).</p><p>It took me 13 hours to complete just the first draft, 6 more hours to render the second draft, and 2 more hours to convince the event lead that I used 19 hours to make this 1.5 minute video lol. Looking back, the video I put together was hardly a hype video, nonetheless, putting my skills into use, was surprised how much more confident&#x2F;conpedent I felt, knowing that I can help people around me in more ways than one.</p><h2 id="Term-Project-Mentor"><a href="#Term-Project-Mentor" class="headerlink" title="Term Project Mentor"></a>Term Project Mentor</h2><img src="../images/2020-12-10/term-project-f20.png" alt="Placeholder, please don't sue me if you are in the picture :')" style=""><span class="image-caption">Placeholder, please don't sue me if you are in the picture :')</span><p>I was lucky enough to have great students as my TP mentee to begin with. Every one of my mentee was on time to every meeting, all past MVP by the deadline, respond to my email spam within 2 hours, and all reached out for help when they needed it, which made my job, so, so much easier.</p><p>It was a pleasure working with them, and they also taught me that, when students hit a threshold on coding proficiency, debugging helps were no longer their top priority in TP. Some wished to tackle a problem they are interested in, some wanted a good score to boost their overall grades, and some just tried to have some fun. Understand other’s motivation and help them fulfill that, felt that was something I leraned working with them, even after being a TP mentor.</p><h2 id="Professor-OH"><a href="#Professor-OH" class="headerlink" title="Professor OH"></a>Professor OH</h2><img src="../images/2020-12-10/ohq.png" alt="Placeholder, please don't sue me if you are in the picture :')" style=""><span class="image-caption">Placeholder, please don't sue me if you are in the picture :')</span><p>Not that I didn’t expect students coming to these, but I was shooked how much less office hours was about professors, when we did them online. During that semester specifically, professor would invite student into a breakout room and talk individually, leaving the rest of queue waiting in the main room with the moderator TA.</p><p>Have considered myself a listener more than a storyteller, so it was always a bit awkwards, stuck with a room full with students, looking at each other, trying to find a topic to chat about, AFTER I have asked them how the weather is in Pittsrbugh 27 times :’).</p><p>Nonetheless, felt that was where I observed the most from other students and TAs. Fake birthday letter someone wrote to their penmate, where the professor got their hawaiian shirt (it was from Amazon), what people ate for lunch, conversations&#x2F;stories like these made me reazlied we were much, much more complicated than just TAs&#x2F;students, and it was nice getting to know them beyond the scope of the course :).</p><h2 id="Burnout"><a href="#Burnout" class="headerlink" title="Burnout"></a>Burnout</h2><p>This TA position required about 12-15 hours of commitment weekly, equivlent to a 12 unit course at the university. Burn out was something that I felt that semester, with turbulance in and outside of the course, I was again a bit lost on what I wish to do in the future. Instead of going it through myself though, the support from students&#x2F;TA was, overwhleming to say the very least.</p><p>Some took the time and recognized the time that I put into this job, some gave me advices on how I should approach other’s feedback. I got compared to Master Oogway once (didn’t know what that was and had to search it up lol), listened to others talk about their struggles outside of the course and how they attempted to resolve it.</p><p>Looking back, still not sure how helpful these was, I felt I have done quite a terrible job at understanding these, but if anything, I was happy that I wasn’t alone going through these, and appreciated their company along the way.</p><h2 id="Ending-Thoughts"><a href="#Ending-Thoughts" class="headerlink" title="Ending Thoughts"></a>Ending Thoughts</h2><p>I guess I was conviced, towards the end of the semester, on why being a TA is ‘fun and exciting’, and something people wish to continue doing ‘until they graduate’. It was less about the materials you get to teach your student, and definitely not the pay :&#x2F;. To me it was more about the experience, working with people that I look up to, talkiong with others that I may not otherwise have the chance to meet, and learn about different ways about approacing problems.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Some takeaways from frist semester being a TA. Enjoyed small interactions with other fellow TAs, made a hype video for the hackathon, guided students as a TP mentor, and dealt with burnt out (learn to have fun).</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Teaching Assistant and Recitation</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20201118/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20201118/</id>
    <published>2020-11-18T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-15T04:23:37.254Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nervous and anxious on this new role, in the two recitation sections that I got assigned to, felt I was taught more by my partner TAs and students, than I have taught them computer science.</p><h2 id="Silence"><a href="#Silence" class="headerlink" title="Silence"></a>Silence</h2><p>I wished to minimize silence in any social interactions, felt the existence of it came from me not asking the right question, or my counterparts being confused on what I said. The mere presence of silence was, akward to me at the time, and that’s exactly what occured in the majority of the recitation when I got up and teach :’). Even when recitations that semester being entirely on zoom, whenever no one answers my call, I can almost touch the akward silence floating in my bedroom.</p><p>Funny enough though, my teaching partner in the eailer recitation was never afraid of that. Instead of panicking (like me), she would intentionally pauses for a moment whenever she finishes a sentence.</p><p>Counterintuitive at the time, but it did make sense. Compare to us, who have learned the material in advance, with the solution right in front of us, students in recitations have little idea on what’s going on, and would oftentime need some moment to process everything we said &amp; asked. By keeping some instances of silence, she allowed students to breath, reflect on the material, recall for the process of problem solving, and also for her to process what she wants to say next :).</p><h2 id="Voice-Fluctuation"><a href="#Voice-Fluctuation" class="headerlink" title="Voice Fluctuation"></a>Voice Fluctuation</h2><p>Rather than observing this from my recitation partner in the latter section, voice fluctuation was something she wished to learn, something her sister is appreantly great at.</p><p>In her words, the way we present material are just as important as the material itself, and by shifting our tone of voice, we highlight things that’s important and deprioritize things that’s not, helping students to understand better, without actively interpreting what we say B).</p><p>As I attempted to learn this alongside with her, different ways of direct student’s attention, was something broader about presentation that I witnessed while she teaches. Things like present visulizations with contrasting colors, align pseudo code with actual solutions, bring up questions that student might have without them asking for it. Felt she understood her student and viewed problems from their perspective, which helps her to allocate time&#x2F;attention on more confusing topics, gave students some idea on what’s important&#x2F;will be seen throughout the future, and what’s not.</p><p>On a side note, as much as she tried to fluctuate her voice that semester, she always sounds excited during recitation, not sure if these students ever figured out what was going on….</p><h2 id="Say-‘I-Don’t-Know’"><a href="#Say-‘I-Don’t-Know’" class="headerlink" title="Say ‘I Don’t Know’"></a>Say ‘I Don’t Know’</h2><p>With a weaker grasp on the course material compare to other TAs, even when I left space for silence and bettered my presentation, I often would be just as confused, when student asks follow up questions regarding solutions, or clearfication on course concepts.</p><p>With all the options that I had, admitting incapability were usually my last resort. The moment that I say such phrase, I felt, weak and incompetent as a TA. TAs that I look up to always seem to know what to say, regardless of scenarios in front of them, and everytime that I say ‘I don’t know’, the gap between me and these people just seems to get, wider and larger.</p><p>And that’s where I was taught by my recitation students. Only towards the end of the semester that I realized, most student I met doesn’t mind when I say ‘I don’t know’, they care more about what I say after that. Whether it is to look it up on the web, let my partner TA in recitation chime in, or to do some research and get back to them through email. Understanding that my job is to provide the best possible answer, and I have more than one way of doing so, it did make me feel less intimidated, whenever a student rises their hand in the end of every problem.</p><h2 id="Ending-Thoughts"><a href="#Ending-Thoughts" class="headerlink" title="Ending Thoughts"></a>Ending Thoughts</h2><p>Rather than saying I learned, these were things that I observed, things that I want to work on in the future. I wish one day I can leave myself some time to think evertime before I speak, convey my emotion and thoughts by rising and lowering my voice, and be more honest with others, including myself.</p><p>Going back to these recitations itself though, knowing that my path would unlikly cross again with these people, I guess it’s now safe for me to say, it was nothing but joy working with them this semester, they were some of the best people I’ve met, and I wish them the best in coming chapters of their jounrey :).</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Some takeaways from frist semester being a TA. Started to embrace akward silence, practiced voice fluctuations, and learned to say &#39;I don&#39;t know&#39;.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>15-112 Simulator</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20200429/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20200429/</id>
    <published>2020-04-29T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-11T04:04:08.810Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ThNc4N_0Bo8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>Multiple time have I thought to write about this, though I never felt I can talk much about this project, despite being the author.</p><p>The idea of 15-112 Simulator came directly from my TP mentor, most of the feature in game are credited to TAs&#x2F;professors that I talked to, the project itself was below average on both complexity and effective lines of code, not to mention the code structure, I only realized I can create a reuseable button class after I finsihed the project lol.</p><p>Regardless, that four weeks of TP did teach me things outside of computer science and coding, and these are what I wish to draw down here.</p><h2 id="Ask-For-Help"><a href="#Ask-For-Help" class="headerlink" title="Ask For Help"></a>Ask For Help</h2><p>Back in highschool I was pretty reluctant to reach out in most situations, felt like I can handle everything on my own. During TP it was eh, a completely different story. There were times where it took me hours to figure a feature out, only to realize later that it broke other parts of my project :’).</p><p>It was, quite a stressful time, but even then I didn’t really think about asking for help, as I thought my code has became so complex that only a few could comprehend. And as expected, every TA that I met during office hour were quite confused on what I wrote, but it wasn’t a waste of time, to my surprise.</p><p>Some TAs left advices on coding best practices (which I only started following after the term project), some gave me alternatives features that’s more doable, and there was one TA, who sat with me for over an hour, half naked on Zoom, just to figure out how I can run my game without crashing the canvas three seconds later. Nathan, if you ever happens to read this, thank you.</p><p>Being completely honest, even after going through office hours, most of the bug I encountered ended up still not getting resovled, and oftentimes I had to figure ways around them. I rarely got what I asked for when I reachout for help, but the passion shown by these TAs, along with a sense of responsibility they posses, was something that left impressions on me in coming semesters.</p><h2 id="Listen-and-Understand"><a href="#Listen-and-Understand" class="headerlink" title="Listen and Understand"></a>Listen and Understand</h2><p>One sad things about making a game on a course is that, you only have a limited view on what it is like; and if you want to get a more objective view of it, you have to ask for other’s input.</p><p>And this was probably the single thing that I appreciate the most, being forced to ask for opnions and feedbacks, consantly. I learned to pick up words that my counterpart is using, rephrase what they are trying to convey, and ask for clearfications whenever I don’t understand.</p><p>Besides gaining experience on reaching out, was surprised how many idas I got just by talking with others. Almost every feature in the game were taken inspiration from one of the professor&#x2F;TA&#x2F;student who are involved in the course at the time. Compare to doing things solely by myself, things does get a lot eaiser when you have other people by your side helping you out.</p><p>This was also the time where I realized that, yeah everyone in CMU is smarter than me, as much as I don’t want to admit :’).</p><h2 id="Reflecting-on-College"><a href="#Reflecting-on-College" class="headerlink" title="Reflecting on College"></a>Reflecting on College</h2><p>Back in highschool I was pretty excited about college, thought it would be a time to learn something new, and a place to change myself a little. TP season happens to be the time where a global pandemic hits, so I ended up moving back to California to live with my family.</p><p>Sitting in my old bedroom, realized that, after a semester of college, I am still very much the same person lol. And knowing that nothing really changed despite my best effort, I sort of lost motivation for most things that semester, this project included, as I wasn’t so sure about what I want to do in coming semesters.</p><p>It was a bit hard to get myself to write code during that week of TP, remember laying on bed, wishing everything to be over soon, only to wake up the next morning, found out nothing has really changed, and there are now more works left for me to do.</p><p>Not the best time I had in college, but this was also the time where I get to think back on my college experience, adjust my expectaions, and reflect them directly on my project in the end. Going back to reaching out and listening to others, turns out I wasn’t the only person who felt that way in a global pandemic, and surprisingly, not the only one who struggled to complete things. Thanks to everyone that I met during that period of time, was able to collect myself together, and finished this project at the last possible minute.</p><h2 id="Ending-Thoughts"><a href="#Ending-Thoughts" class="headerlink" title="Ending Thoughts"></a>Ending Thoughts</h2><p>I got more out of this project than I have contributed to it, and felt quite grateful on what I’ve experienced, along with everything I’ve learned. I am still passive, uncurious, blunt, and still have a hard time understanding people around me, but realizing that there are more than one way I can resolve this, and I don’t have to do this along, this was probably the best lesson I got in 2020 :D.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Knowing little about coding coming into the University, I didn&#39;t expect myself to have this fun creating something I had in mind. It was also, one of the turning point for me I would say? As it setted me up for things I never thought would be possible for me.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Trip to China</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20191220/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20191220/</id>
    <published>2019-12-20T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-15T04:22:24.983Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="../images/2019-12-20/ina-lolo-me.jpg" alt="With some of my relatives, Ina and Lolo :D" style=""><span class="image-caption">With some of my relatives, Ina and Lolo :D</span><p>This is the second time I was in China since I left. Stunned by how modern my city has became, I was more drawn to the people I got to meet, as it has being just about 3 years since we last chatted.</p><h2 id="Lolo-and-Ina"><a href="#Lolo-and-Ina" class="headerlink" title="Lolo and Ina"></a>Lolo and Ina</h2><p>If you can’t see it from the picture above, I really like Lolo and Ina :D. Three years no see, we still had a good time chatting at the dinner, hearing things happening in the new school Lolo went to, plus all the fun things happened at Ina’s kindergarden.</p><p>5 years apart from Lolo and 12 years apart from Ina, It’s quite nice to see how similar we still are. We all played piano when we were kids, enjoyed watching cartoons, and likes to order 东坡肉 when we are at a resterant.</p><h2 id="Kimi"><a href="#Kimi" class="headerlink" title="Kimi"></a>Kimi</h2><p>Kimi was one of the only non-relatives that we visited during our stay. We lived in the same neighborhood back in China, played together for a few times, and have known each other ever since.</p><p>If I was surprised when I met Lolo and Ina, I was shocked when I met Kimi lol. Recently with COVID, has being video chatting with Kimi every now and then. Independent, active, and competitive, she is now studying at a high school in the UK, playing lacross and compete for her high school team, started learning German, taught herself both C and Python, and have coded programs that would take me hours to code myself :’). Kimi wants to major in Math and Computer science when she is in college, and want to be a reseracher&#x2F;mathmatian once she graduate.</p><p>Kimi’s passion towards winning, her sense of presistance across whatever she is intreted in, has always being something that I looked up to. She is probably prepping for her college aplication as I am writing this, wish her best of luck out there :D.</p><h2 id="Grandpa"><a href="#Grandpa" class="headerlink" title="Grandpa"></a>Grandpa</h2><p>When I felt everything has changed, my grandpa stayed, eh, exactly the same lol. Still the same hobby, same stories that he tells, same color of jacket when going outside, and the same facial expression when we finally needed to leave.</p><p>Being in the army for most of his life, my grandpa kept his rountine 20 years after he retired. He would often wake up at around 5:30 in the morning, take a hour long walk around the West Lake, buy some breakfast at the stand he always goes to, walk back to the house, sit in the living room, watch 朝闻天下 while eating his breakfast at exactly 7.</p><p>Why do I know these, well, waking me up at 5:30 and drag me on his walk happens to be a part of his routine while I was there :’).</p><p>Aside from this rather unpleasent experience though, I did enjoy the stay with my grandpa. We would play chinese chess together and laugh at each other’s play (okay mostly mine) for the whole afternoon, walk to the grocery market to get dinner, and talk about all the changes in the city while I wasn’t here.</p><p>My grandpa refers people at my school as 美国佬, the language we speak as 美国话, and ask me to teach him that one day, so he could come to my place for a visit. He still doesn’t know which school that I went to, but this never gets in the way of him showing how proud he is about me, whether it’s in person, or on video chats yesterday :).</p><h2 id="Ending-thoughts"><a href="#Ending-thoughts" class="headerlink" title="Ending thoughts"></a>Ending thoughts</h2><p>Aside from how fast time flied, realized how people centric I am from this trip. Didn’t feel much when I walked around my elementary school, but memories flushed back after talking with teachers who used to teach me there, the exact same with my relatives, Kimi, and grandpa. It was a great time meeting these people again, happy that we got the chance to go back and visit.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Second time being back to China, met up with Lolo &amp; Ina, Kimi, and Grandpa. Felt time flied, and how people centric I was.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>High School Graduation</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20190612/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20190612/</id>
    <published>2019-06-12T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-15T04:21:39.377Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="../images/2019-06-12/high-school-graduation.jpg" alt="When the principle annonced we have finally graduated we all throw our hats up" style=""><span class="image-caption">When the principle annonced we have finally graduated we all throw our hats up</span><p>Lucky for us, our graduation ceremony was also the 10th annivacery for our high school, plus the last in person one before COVID hit. Our friends and parents filled the entire stadium hours before the ceremony started, and the local police had to come and help direct the traffic lol.</p><p>The ceremony itself was, quite exciting, it was a place for everyone to celebrate the past, present, and future all at the same time. I didn’t remember most of it to be honest, but was quite happy when the principle handed me the diploma. Using my host family’s word, I am offically an educated man now B).</p><p>Thinking back to my four years at this school, I honestly can’t recall anything significant. I took courses just as every other student in the school would, tried my best to maintain GPA, did swim and water polo for a few semesters, met some friends, and yeah, that’s about it :). I didn’t feel much of a connection to this school or my class, as most of the people I knew have gradued a year in advance.</p><p>At the time I already knew where I would be going next fall for univeristy, and was pretty excited for it. I didn’t pay too close of an attention to the ceremony, in that very moment, my mind has already wondered to college, eager to find out what my next four year is going to be like.</p><p>Uncertainty, relief, along with a bit of excitment? It was an intresting experience overall, felt this ceremony was more like a new begining, compare to an end.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Uncertainty, relief, excitment, some thoughts during high school graduation.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Trip to Seattle</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20180620/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20180620/</id>
    <published>2018-06-26T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-11T04:02:01.764Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="../images/2018-06-20/seattle-trip.jpg" alt="Picture taken at Pike's Place with my mom, first Starbucks :D" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">Picture taken at Pike's Place with my mom, first Starbucks :D</span><p>Being the first trip I planned from begining to end, have ran into quite a few issues. Just about a year has past since the trip, thought it would be nice for me to record these thoughts, just in case I have do someting similar in the future.</p><h2 id="Make-a-More-Versatile-Plan"><a href="#Make-a-More-Versatile-Plan" class="headerlink" title="Make a More Versatile Plan"></a>Make a More Versatile Plan</h2><p>The third day that we were in Seattle, we got stucked in the hotel elevator, when we tried to come down and grab some breakfast :’). Luckly noo one died in the end (except the hotel manager lol), but we did lose a few precious hour of that morning, and the plan I got for the day had to be cancelled. In the end, we walked around Pike’s Place and took some pictures, checkout the image above if you want a reference :D.</p><p>What I realized was that, rather than making a plan composed entirely on when to do what, should have instead, make another category of things we can do at any given moment. Walk around Pike’s Place, visit the Central Public Library, or even just to go and checkout the Chinatown. These events, although trivial, would make a trip more fluid and flexible, helps me better adjust to the current situation of the trip.</p><h2 id="Have-Half-of-Day-of-Nothing"><a href="#Have-Half-of-Day-of-Nothing" class="headerlink" title="Have Half of Day of Nothing"></a>Have Half of Day of Nothing</h2><p>So I did have that on my original plan, but mainly because I ran out of things to do lol.</p><p>It was an afternoon towards the end of the trip, me and my mom ended up sitting in the hotel room, and chatted about the trip as a whole, things that we individually saw, funny pictures we took, and reflections we had.</p><p>To my surprise, that afternoon became one of the highlights through the trip. I did enjoy walking around the city and visiting new places, but really appreciate that short afternoon of doing nothing, reflecting things that we did, and exchange thoughts on how we can improve.</p><p>Might be because who I was with, my mom, who is much wiser and more mature than me. However, when places we visit would eventually get forgotten, soviourers we bought would at one day be thrown away, I still remember reflections my mom had, along with things that she said. This half day of nothing may be different for everyone, a time to organize pictures they took, a moment to catch up on sleep, but for me, thought it was a great oppotunity, getting feedback from the trip, and take notes on how I can do better on the next.</p><h2 id="Enjoy-the-Trip"><a href="#Enjoy-the-Trip" class="headerlink" title="Enjoy the Trip"></a>Enjoy the Trip</h2><p>Really didn’t think about this until much later after the trip, but with more trips I took throughout the year, looking back, I didn’t quite ‘enjoy’ this trip compare to the other. I was solely looking for popular places around Seattle, and blindly adding them to the trip plan.</p><p>My mom enjoys taking pictures, so Chinatown or a longer visit at Chihuly Garden of Glass, would probably have being a better option for her. I perfer going somewhere quiet and just sit there, so should have marked a longer day trip at Mount Rainier, or even make a stop at the public library.</p><p>Now all that being said, it took me a while to figure out what I enjoyed on a trip. Nonetheless, do felt like I could have done a better job, at least at communciating with my parents while making the travel plan, asking them what their preference was, and make a trip that they would have enjoyed more.</p><h2 id="Ending-Thoughts"><a href="#Ending-Thoughts" class="headerlink" title="Ending Thoughts"></a>Ending Thoughts</h2><p>Truth be told, I still didn’t know where Seattle is at, even after we finished the trip lol. But it was, all in all, a great time visiting there :D.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">First time visiting Seattle, also the first trip I planned completely on my own, some reflections, some thoughts, and things I wish I would have known before the trip.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Wofie, Lizzy, and Ares</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20180318/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20180318/</id>
    <published>2018-03-18T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-11T04:02:42.199Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thinking back to my stay, these three puppies were almost always the first thing that cames to my mind. Being someone who never really had a pet, dealing with three was, quite an unique experience.</p><h2 id="Wofie"><a href="#Wofie" class="headerlink" title="Wofie"></a>Wofie</h2><img src="../images/2018-03-18/wofie.jpeg" alt="Wofie, not very happy that the shutter sound woke him up" style="width:80%; height:80%;"><span class="image-caption">Wofie, not very happy that the shutter sound woke him up</span><p>Wofie is the cloest defnition I have, if you asked me what a dog is like 5 years ago. Active, loyal, attention craving, as a Schnauzer with a giant ego, Wofie is, well, not very pleasent to interact with, to say the very least :’).</p><p>I tend prefer peace and quiet, so the sole existance of Wofie has, bothered me a little. He would be running around the house constantly, marking his territory, asserting his dominance over the other two (and sometimes me), if we ever left him unchecked for more than ten minutes. He would come over and yell at us if we are having too much fun without him at the dinner, and brak for hours, just to chase the bird outside away, who is merely trying to built a nest.</p><p>As unpleasent as he was to deal with, as the most straightforward one out of all three, Wofie was the first that I was able to understood. If he barks he wants to go outside, if he growls someone is in his way, and if he does anything else, well, he is probably looking for a treat…</p><p>Thinking back, Wofie might just have being the most brilliant human trainer I have met. He is honest, straightforward, doesn’t hide away his feelings and never overthinks, which helped us greatly to gave him what he wanted.</p><h2 id="Lizzy"><a href="#Lizzy" class="headerlink" title="Lizzy"></a>Lizzy</h2><img src="../images/2018-03-18/lizzy.jpeg" alt="Lizzy, sleeping on the bed where I sleep :')" style="width:50%; height:50%;"><span class="image-caption">Lizzy, sleeping on the bed where I sleep :')</span><p>A Dachshund and Schnauzer mix, Lizzy remained as my host family’s favorite through my time there. She is ‘Liz’ for host mom, and ‘my baby girl’ for host dad. She enjoys the first 10 minutes of every walk, likes to sleep on the sofa whenever someoen is there, and loves to destory toys, whenever we buy her something squeaky :’).</p><p>Aside from her charisma, Lizzy has a sense of curiocity that can only be found from a puppy. She would come and sniff every package delivered at the front porch, and meeting new people with some lick on the face. In the summer of 2017, that curiocity got her bitten by a rattle snake, along with three nights of stay in the pet hospital. After that the urge of getting to know everything has rapidly cooled down, though still, whenever she would hear someone standing at the door, she would still rush to the door, stand up with her tails swingglings from side to side, just to see who is there.</p><h2 id="Ares"><a href="#Ares" class="headerlink" title="Ares"></a>Ares</h2><img src="../images/2018-03-18/ares.jpeg" alt="Ares with his innocent look" style="width:80%; height:80%;"><span class="image-caption">Ares with his innocent look</span><p>The host family’s son adopted Ares and named him after the god of war. Contrary to this aggresive name though, as a pit bull, Ares is surprisingly chill and quite, just like me B).</p><p>Sleeping and walking are really the only two activies Ares does. On a typicaly day, he would drag himself to the living room sofa, lay there comfortably until the afternoon, where the host mom (and sometimes I) would take him for a walk. After the walk, he would return to his favorite spot on the sofa, sleep there until the evening, where he would go to my host dad’s room and enjoy the rest of the night there.</p><p>As low energy as Ares sound, he turns into a different dog whenever he is outside. He would drag me forward, dig holes on the ground, bite the leash and growls at me if I am going too slow :’).</p><p>Ares loves anywhere but the house, to the point where he ran away, twice, during the time of my stay. The first time he ran all the way to my high school (which is about 10 minutes by car and 30 minutes by foot), and got carried back by some very kind construction workers across the street. The second time he appeantly he ran to the other side of the hill, it was late at night, all we knew was, he got taken back by a even nicer driver who, eh, almost hit him on the street.</p><p>We now get nervous evertime Ares eyes at the front door lol, though as troublesome as he is, would say Ares has been a great partner whenever I decides to do work at the living room sofa. He never craves for attention, seldomly barks even when there are bird chipping outside, and simply rolls over if he wants some belly scarch, letting me enjoys my afternoon without constantly looking out for him :).</p><h2 id="Ending-Thoughts"><a href="#Ending-Thoughts" class="headerlink" title="Ending Thoughts"></a>Ending Thoughts</h2><p>It would be an exaggeration compare these dogs to people I lived with during my stay, though I do think back to these interactions, more than any students who were there. Always be on my bed when I wanted to take a nap, swallow food on the floor faster than I could pick them back up, play dead and smile at exactly halfway of a walk, still not sure if I ever enjoyed their company. Nonetheless though, being something that has feelings and emotions, they were one of the first creatures that I actively try to understand, and something that still lingers around my memory, even today :).</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Whenever I talk about my host family, these three puppies are one of the first thing that came to my mind. Not that they played that important of a role, but a sense of consistancy was something that always kept them in my mind.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="https://yize.blog/20000908/"/>
    <id>https://yize.blog/20000908/</id>
    <published>2000-09-08T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T01:28:52.308Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello and welcome! Want to use this post to talk a bit more about who I am, along with what I wish to accomplish using this website.</p><h2 id="About-Me"><a href="#About-Me" class="headerlink" title="About Me"></a>About Me</h2><p>Really wasn’t joking when I say I am not great with self intros, but anyway lol.</p><p>My name is Yize Shen, currently a university student. As for personality, got ISFJ for Myers Briggs, and a type 6 for Enneagram.</p><p>My favorite color is grey, favorite ice cream flavor is vanilla, enjoy listening to lofi hip hop musics, play both Minecraft and Terraria, currently ranked Iron II in League of Legend, and love cats and dogs equally :].</p><p>Aside from school, usually enjoy spending time by myself. Reading, playing video games, translating, writing jounrals, etc. Though recently did start exploring things I don’t typically do, took a few lessons at a dance studio, learned a bit about acapella, watched a few series on Netflix, attempted to draw using Figma, and applied to be a volunteer at Beijing 2022 Winter Olympic. They were, surprisingly fun I would say? Do think I also appreciate making connections with people other than myself, doing things together in a group.</p><h2 id="About-This-Website"><a href="#About-This-Website" class="headerlink" title="About This Website"></a>About This Website</h2><p>As mentioned in <a target="_self" href="https://yizeshen7.github.io/about/">About</a>, was planning on using this site as a place to record my life and occasionally, thoughts and feelings.</p><p>Like any elder man you see walking on the street, I also tend to forget about things easily :’). To combat servere memory loses, started jounraling back in 2019, just to have a place to put down things I wish to remember. Overtime, felt jounraling has helped me relive my state of mind whenever I look back, so wish this website to be the same.</p><p>Aside from recording my life, want to use this website as a tool to improve my communciation skills. Compare to most people I met who are my age, often felt not as efficiente, formulating thoughts and expressing them in a concise way. Don’t think writing posts on a website would directly help me with that, but hey, for an introvert, this is a giant leap I am taking buddy :’).</p><p>Lastly, if anything, want to use this site for others who wish to know a bit about me. Consider myself pretty straightforward and simple minded, but also realized that, too often I would keep opinons&#x2F;thoughts&#x2F;ideas to myself, rather than expressing them to my counterparts. I don’t wish to be a mystery to most people, and especially people who I surround myself with. This website is intended to be a passive way for me to share a bit about who I am and what I’ve experienced, just incase you are curious :].</p><p>All in all, plan to use this website to record my life, practice my writing skills, and let others to know a bit more about me. Curious to see how this would go, and yeah, thanks for reading.</p><p>On a side note, if you are reading this and have a way to contact me, feel free to reach out! Would love to hear thoughts and feedbacks, if you have any :D.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Incase you are wondering, no I didn&#39;t write a blog post the day I was born lol. Want to use this post to talk a bit about who I am, along with my plans for this website.</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
